<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Sessions xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<Session>
		<Title>.NET TDD Immersion (Tuesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>TDD Immersion covers everything you need to know to do test-driven development on real .NET projects. We'll go over stuff like how to write tests first, how to refactor your code to make it easier to test, mocking frameworks like Moq, dependency injection with StructureMap, and other TDD tips and tricks I've learned from doing TDD over the years.

We'll also walk through a sample ASP.NET MVC web app and show you how you might set up an actual project, work with ORMs and data access layers, set up your test projects, and make things easy to test.  We'll end with some TDD practice to help you hone your TDD skills, so bring your laptop (or pair up with someone who has one). TDD has revolutionized the way that I write code and it can do the same for you! 
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Indigo</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jon Kruger</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/NET-TDD-Immersion-Tuesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>a02b4998-bc99-49ae-8b3a-19c3598735eb</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jon-Kruger</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>&#x201C;Users are Losers! They&#x2019;ll Like Whatever we Make&#x201D; and Other Fallacies. </Title>
		<Abstract>If this sounds familiar it is time to make big changes or look for a new job. Failing your users will only end badly. In this session we&#x2019;ll look at the assumptions that are all-too-often made about users, usability and the User Experience (UX). In response to each of these misguided statements Carol will provide a quick method you can conduct with little or no resources to debunk these myths. </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Carol J. Smith</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Design/UX</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Users-are-Losers-Theyll-Like-Whatever-we-Make-and-Other-Fallacies-</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>8a0540d2-3d46-4aea-93da-7faa75918666</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Carol-J-Smith</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>A Practical Guide to CSS3 - CANCELLED</Title>
		<Abstract>THIS SESSION HAS BEEN CANCELLED

Modern web applications push the envelope toward feeling more and more "native", and today many developers are taking a single-page approach to building complex apps.  As our interactions become more complicated so do our styling requirements.  Animations, transitions, highly stylized elements, web fonts, responsive layouts all add to the complexity of our projects.  In this talk, JC will help untangle some of the features of CSS3 that we can use today.  He'll show us some helpful tools like SASS and Bourbon for helping to better organize our styling while maintaining cross-browser compatibility.

This talk will focus on:

- CSS3 animations and transitions
- Advanced layout with CSS3 Flex-box
- Element styling (shadows, border radius, multiple backgrounds, gradients, etc)
- Typography, web fonts and icon fonts
- Using media queries
- An introduction to SASS and the Bourbon library</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>JC Grubbs</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Design/UX</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/A-Practical-Guide-to-CSS3--CANCELLED</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>b14e3d36-c3f6-485e-98a5-8250fa02ded1</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/JC-Grubbs</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Advanced ASP.NET MVC - CANCELLED</Title>
		<Abstract>SESSION CANCELLED 

In this session we will look at different techniques that leverage extensibility points within ASP.NET MVC to make the most of your applications.  If you've ever wanted to know how you can do more with less within MVC, this is a session you don't want to miss!</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Advanced</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Javier Lozano</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Advanced-ASPNET-MVC--CANCELLED</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>d1c503f1-c8b7-4eca-9232-6870411daa57</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Javier-Lozano</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Advanced Unit Testing Design and How it Applies to Stakeholders</Title>
		<Abstract>Automated testing provides a way for developers to validate a certain level of quality. But, automated testing provides much, much more than that. Automated tests form the basis of many types of documentation, if you let them.

This session details how you can build on your automated testing successes by detailing how organize and name your test classes and test methods to make your tests work for you. Your tests can be the reference documentation for your internal APIs. Tests can validate code but they can also validate requirements and acceptance criteria. When tests are well organized, they can be used to round-trip requirements and acceptance criteria to give stakeholders full round-trip validation by generating human-readable documentation based on certain tests. This session also details ways to reflect certain types of tests to document how tests are validating requirements and acceptance criteria.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Advanced</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Peter Ritchie</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Advanced-Unit-Testing-Design-and-How-it-Applies-to-Stakeholders</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>b68ff955-5c94-40d9-943a-7ae8a97df315</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Peter-Ritchie</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Aftermash Party</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-11T23:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-12T01:00:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Aftermash-Party</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>e78c3258-22d5-47a6-b5bb-4cc1bff29ffa</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Agile Servant Leadership practices with Moral Authority: WOOF</Title>
		<Abstract>This interactive session will share emerging Lean &amp; Agile leadership techniques for management that we practice to support servant leadership. We will discuss decision making techniques such as Fist of Five, 6 Thinking Hats, demonstrate collaboration techniques such as Collaboration 8, Program Alignment Walls, Key Performance Indicators, Sales Alignment Wall, Lady Bugs, and discuss how to lead with Moral Authority.  </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jon Stahl</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Agile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Agile-Servant-Leadership-practices-with-Moral-Authority-WOOF</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>ef7cd65a-6821-49ec-9204-3a5ea54349ae</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jon-Stahl</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Agile, Lean, and the Space Between</Title>
		<Abstract>In early 2001, "Agile" was coined as the umbrella term for Scrum, XP, ASD, DSDM, Crystal, and a few other methodologies. In 2003, Mary and Tom Poppendieck published the book "Lean Software Development: An Agile Toolkit", and the term Lean Software Development became known among a subset of the larger Agile community.

For years, one could assume that any development group trying to improve its approach to software was applying some form of Agile Software Development methodology. In the last couple of years, Lean Software Development has seen a surge in popularity. Some groups adopting Lean perceive it as an alternative to Agile processes like Scrum, and express a sense of elitism and superiority, having "moved beyond Agile".

While Agile Software Development and Lean Software Development originate from different sources, they are actually closely related and share a great deal of overlap. In this talk attendees will discover where each came from, and just how much of Agile and Lean are shared in the space between.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Barry Hawkins</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Agile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Agile-Lean-and-the-Space-Between</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>50a537ea-2bc0-4315-8604-b6a41ab60c01</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Barry-Hawkins</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Android Custom Views, the Right Way</Title>
		<Abstract>Android is a very powerful framework that has just about everything you'll need out of the box. For everything else, Android includes a sophisticated and powerful framework for creating the crazy UI you have in mind. Learn the three main methods we use to create custom views, and all the tips you'll need to write code that fits right in with the Android Open Source Project.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Michael Pardo</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Android-Custom-Views-the-Right-Way</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>1005d08b-6475-475e-837a-6aaf3a2b34f5</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Michael-Pardo</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>AngularJS: The HTML of the Future</Title>
		<Abstract>Come learn how AngularJS (http://www.angularjs.org/) can extend HTML vocabulary for your own applications and build reusable HTML components that you can share across projects. We'll also focus on how easy it is to connect to services and bind to any data source to quickly build up very rich applications. All demonstrations, code, and slides from the presentation will be freely available on github for your own use.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>John Lindquist</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/AngularJS-The-HTML-of-the-Future</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>acb21362-e13b-43a5-ab7a-a25ae8a45a36</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/John-Lindquist</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Applying Pizza Delivery Lessons to Emergency Helicopter Dispatching</Title>
		<Abstract>A case study for building a set of custom applications to request and monitor emergency helicopters for use in hospitals.

For this project we decided to build our cloud app with a hodgepodge of parts: Heroku, Ruby, Sinatra, CouchDB and Redis. and for our user interface: a native iOS app running on iPads - with a JSON REST API tying it all together.

We will answer questions like: "Where does pub/sub beat queuing?", "Do I really need to cache my REST calls?", and "Why doesn't this scale - I added more memory?"</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>William Klos</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Ruby</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Applying-Pizza-Delivery-Lessons-to-Emergency-Helicopter-Dispatching</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>2d74b7d3-57f4-4bb9-95d0-981a3cfb3cdb</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/William-Klos</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Atomic Scala (Wednesday Full Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>This seminar is based on our book Atomic Scala, which takes away the pain of learning by breaking subjects into the smallest chunks we could (we call them "atoms"). Even (dedicated) first-time programmers can learn Scala with this book, but the design also makes it the most expedient way for experienced programmers to get started with Scala.
We present each Atom (chapter) in the book as a very short lecture, followed by an exercise period. Atomic concepts make learning Scala easy and fun.
Topics
Scala is an amazing and elegant language. It's also powerful, and overwhelming if you try to absorb it all at once. Our goal is to present the language in small bites that you can quickly grasp, to give you a foundation on which you build more knowledge.
This 1-day precompiler is based on our weeklong format. We want you to finish the day feeling strong and ready to learn more about Scala. To achieve this we have selected a subset of topics that, once learned, allow you to create useful and interesting programs; a base from which you can increase your knowledge. We have carefully trimmed away topics that you don't need to know right away (but that you'll be able to acquire more easily from books or more advanced courses).  We&#x2019;ll send installation instructions prior to CodeMash, so that we can jump right into learning Scala.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Dianne Marsh</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Scala</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Atomic-Scala-Wednesday-Full-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Bruce Eckel</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Bruce Eckel is the author of Thinking in Java and Thinking in C++, and a number of other books on computer programming. He&#x2019;s been in the computer industry for 30 years, periodically gets frustrated and tries to quit, then something like Scala comes along and offers hope and sucks him back in. He&#x2019;s given hundreds of presentations around the world and enjoys putting on alternative conferences and events like The Java Posse Roundup. He is currently studying organizational dynamics, trying to find a new way to organize companies so that working together becomes a joy; you can read about his struggles in this arena at Reinventing-Business.com, while his programming work can be found through www.MindViewInc.com.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>38a02352-c5dd-4289-9b5e-ea0ac9770143</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Dianne-Marsh</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Attendee Party</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-11T00:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T04:55:00Z</End>
		<Room>TBD</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Attendee-Party</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>61a62e86-4e17-4fcd-8154-6156cace01ed</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>BDD in .NET with SpecFlow</Title>
		<Abstract>A key concept of any Agile methodology is communication. It&#x2019;s no longer normal or acceptable for developers to sit and develop applications in isolation from the business. To that end, developers and business domain experts have been trying to find better ways to communicate. While developers tend to speak in terms of &#x201C;code and technology&#x201D; most business domain experts are more comfortable communicating in terms of scenarios, workflows and business rules.
 Test Driven Development (TDD) was the first step in getting these two groups to communicate in the same way. Developers could write unit tests that expressed business requirements with the hope that business users could validate that what was being tested was in fact what the desired behavior was. But, unit tests are still code and while it was better, the communication was still stilted and inefficient.

To help this communication new techniques such as Behavior Driven Development (BDD) and Acceptance Test Driven Development (ATDD) have become popular. Along with these new ideas, new tools like SpecFlow have become popular as a means to express unit tests in a way that the business can better understand and validate.

This session will demonstrate how SpecFlow can be leveraged in your BDD or ATDD practices. In this session you will learn what SpecFlow is and how to integrate it into your .NET project. The Gherkin language and the &#x201C;Given, When, Then&#x201D; paradigm will be explained. You will see how to write tests in a way that business users are not only capable of reading, but can also help you create them.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>James Bender</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/BDD-in-NET-with-SpecFlow</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>7effa95b-0a2d-4fe9-bfcf-f49ff66b07a3</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/James-Bender</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Becoming a software strategist</Title>
		<Abstract>As Software developers we are literally on the front-line everyday.  We&#x2019;re creating software and delivering it at both an exhilarating and sometimes exhausting pace.  We use Agile to get our customer involved in our process.  What we are often missing is getting ourselves involved in our customer&#x2019;s process. In this session you&#x2019;ll learn how to vastly improve the software you deliver by becoming a software strategist. You&#x2019;ll be given the tools that will allow to create a written strategy that any MBA will be impressed with.  You&#x2019;ll learn how to create effective steering committees.  Most importantly, you&#x2019;ll learn how to become a part of strategic decision making before it happens.  Strategy is the essential first step into building great software, by learning and applying these techniques, you be immeasurably helping yourself and your organization.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Bill Heitzeg</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Business</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Becoming-a-software-strategist</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>491c3ac1-f63a-4bdb-a671-408e04204d72</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Bill-Heitzeg</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Beginning Software Craftsmanship (Wednesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>In this interactive session, you'll learn some of the basic principles and practices of writing better quality code: testing and pairing.  You'll work with a variety of partners on coding katas designed to instill best practices that you'll then be ready to apply when next you work on production code.  This session is led by the organizers of the Hudson Software Craftsmanship group and provides a great introduction to the afternoon's Intermediate Software Craftsmanship session (though this is not a prerequisite for that session).  Attendees should already be comfortable with a programming language of their choice and if possible should bring along a laptop computer with their development tools installed, including a unit testing tool. 
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Steve Smith</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Craftsmanship</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Beginning-Software-Craftsmanship-Wednesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Brendan Enrick</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Brendan Enrick works for Telerik as a Lead Developer in their Services Division. Brendan is one of the founders and organizers of the Hudson Software Craftsmanship group, which meets monthly in Hudson, Ohio, between Akron and Cleveland. Brendan keeps a software development blog focusing on software craftsmanship, agile, and other development topics. His blog can be found at http://Brendan.Enrick.com/ and his twitter alias is @Brendoneus.
</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>9ec7f8a6-a858-43e0-b77c-3c1d0efde51a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Steve-Smith</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Beginning Xbox 360 Development with the XNA Framework</Title>
		<Abstract>While many of us dream of jobs in game development, XNA Game Studio gives you the tools necessary to make and publish your own games for the Xbox Live Indie Games Marketplace. Attendees will given a brief overview of using XNA Game Studio to create software for the Xbox 360. Topics include basic sprite manipulation, controller inputs, and basic collision detection.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Indigo Bay</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Chris Gardner</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Game Development</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Beginning-Xbox-360-Development-with-the-XNA-Framework</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>0c527569-28d7-49b3-a87a-1a197e5d5798</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Chris-Gardner</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Better Metrics for your Team</Title>
		<Abstract>Are you still measuring the performance of your team with Velocity, Estimates vs. Actuals, Code Coverage, Cyclomatic Complexity, and &#x201C;style violations&#x201D;? Are your business stakeholders still in the dark about when they can expect new features? If so, you&#x2019;re missing the boat.

The good news is that there are more powerful and reliable metrics that are cheaper to derive. Trust me, you will love these metrics and they will love you back.

You&#x2019;ll walk away from this session understanding the purpose of capturing metrics, how few you actually need, and participate in an interactive game showing you how to capture them.

Learning outcomes:
* Ability to use Throughput and Cycle Time on your projects to effectively communicate your team's performance to your business stakeholders.
* Ability to use statistical models to provide "when will this get done" answers to your business stakeholders.
* Understanding of the interwoven relationship of Work In Process, Cycle Time, and Throughput.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Nayan Hajratwala</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Software Process</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Better-Metrics-for-your-Team</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>cb8b67e7-09f2-4391-a010-ede0da902769</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Nayan-Hajratwala</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Better Testing with Given/When/Then</Title>
		<Abstract>Do you struggle with writing good tests? Do you want your executable specs to read like real specifications and not just code you have to wade through to understand?

Given/When/Then is an extension library for RSpec designed to take RSpec's excellent DSL for defining English-like specifications and taking it to the next level. Given/When/Then allows developers to clearly state what behaviors are being specified, what are the preconditions for that behavior, and what outcomes are expected under various scenarios.

This talk will cover not only the basics of Given/When/Then, but also best practices for writing readable and robust specifications that are not brittle when faced with code refactoring.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jim Weirich</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Ruby</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Better-Testing-with-GivenWhenThen</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>b5f99df1-4075-4a8a-ba35-39ab4d803ff9</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jim-Weirich</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Breakfast - Friday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-11T13:15:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T14:15:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Breakfast--Friday</URI>
		<EventType>Meal</EventType>
		<Id>ef8d2e86-5b5e-4d4a-bbb8-d25345d2e6a7</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Breakfast - Thursday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-10T12:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T13:00:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Breakfast--Thursday</URI>
		<EventType>Meal</EventType>
		<Id>01a709ee-7df7-4928-aacd-a2f780df4136</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Breakfast - Tuesday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-08T12:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Breakfast--Tuesday</URI>
		<EventType>Meal</EventType>
		<Id>277ba0b4-94d7-4801-bcdb-2b05791341d7</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Breakfast - Wednesday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-09T12:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Breakfast--Wednesday</URI>
		<EventType>Meal</EventType>
		<Id>f1025237-9cfe-41e9-a7cc-c94cca424725</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Budgeting Reality: a Nuanced Discussion on Mock Objects</Title>
		<Abstract>Our community's conversations about mock objects lack nuance, rigor, and thoughtfulness. This talk puts us on a path toward fixing that.

Some say "mocks suck," because they reduce a test's realism and, therefore, our confidence that the code being tested actually works. Others use mocks to demarcate the outer boundary of an application, guarding the test from expensive or external dependencies (e.g. by faking a database or network resource). Still others see mocks as a "setup of last resort", using them only to mitigate the pain of hard-to-test code. Finally, some developers mock out every collaborator in every test, and their rationale is probably the least understood of them all!

This talk will serve as an opinionated (if broad-stroke) survey of the different ways people use test doubles (be they mocks, fakes, stubs, or spies). Our goal will be to establish a more sophisticated means of communicating on the topic. We'll discuss the pros &amp; cons of the different approaches toward mocking, the smells of test double abuse, and the lessons I took away from writing my own test double library. 

Most importantly, the talk will emphasize why knowing what value we want from a test is a prerequisite to knowing the merits of using mock objects to write that test. Reality is expensive, and it's more valuable to some types of tests than to others.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Justin Searls</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Budgeting-Reality-a-Nuanced-Discussion-on-Mock-Objects</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>89864493-664e-499d-b998-547bc90324b0</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Justin-Searls</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Build a Cloud App In an Afternoon With Parse</Title>
		<Abstract>Ideas are cheap, but development time isn't. So what happens when you find yourself with nothing but a great idea and a free afternoon? Using Parse (www.parse.com) can be a great option for getting a cloud app up and running fast, without having to worry about back-end infrastructure, server maintenance, or scaling issues. 

Even if you love building your own APIs, you can use Parse &#xE0; la carte to simplify Push Notifications (iOS &amp; Android), In-App Purchases (iOS) or User Signups &amp; Logins (with password recovery).

We'll dive into the API by going through a real setup and writing a simple web app that you'll be able to interact with immediately. I'll also be showcasing real code examples from more complex apps running Parse for their backend, and run though some prototyping use cases. In addition to the benefits, we'll also discuss some potential drawbacks of using this in a deployed app.

(Note, I do not have any affiliation with Parse. It's just a great service that has saved me countless hours of time, and I'd love to share my experiences with it.)</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Rosewood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Will Dages</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Build-a-Cloud-App-In-an-Afternoon-With-Parse</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>35e37c07-37a5-4563-9e62-478a6912e36a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Will-Dages</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Building against the Microsoft Data Stack</Title>
		<Abstract>WebAPI or OData? WCF or ASMX? XML or JSON? Data is the core of why we build systems and solutions and look for opportunities to automate and simplify. What are the options and when do you make the tradeoffs? In this session, we look at what's new with the Microsoft ADO.NET Entity Framework and explain how it works with Windows Communication Foundation (WCF), Representational State Transfer (REST), and RIA Data Services. We also explore the technologies and the trends that are driving the frameworks to see how to take advantage of these new technologies.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Mike Benkovich</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Building-against-the-Microsoft-Data-Stack</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>aa6686b5-553f-4b3b-8299-034f0d117c1a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Mike-Benkovich</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Building External DSLs for Fun and Profit</Title>
		<Abstract>We've all seen the explosion of fluent interfaces and internal DSLs with the language-oriented features of recent releases of C#. Dynamic languages extend the boundaries even further, where we can bend the programming languages to our will.

But what if we want to move beyond the barriers of the programming language and into actual external, executable DSLs? In this session, we'll look at the landscape of lexers, parsers, grammars and trees to see how we can use these tools to build external DSLs that business users will actually enjoy using. We'll also look at how we can take those trees and transform them into real, executable code.

Finally, we'll see where to use external DSLs (and where not to use them) to build systems with truly dynamic behavior.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Advanced</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jimmy Bogard</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Building-External-DSLs-for-Fun-and-Profit</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>63b77618-3ba3-49d8-834a-55cd6c5262aa</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jimmy-Bogard</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Building Productive iOS 6 Apps (Wednesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>It can't all be about the games; the App Store has lots of other categories, like productivity, utility, business, navigation, lifestyle, and so on. So for this year's afternoon iOS precompiler, we're going to look specifically at some of the features in the iOS SDK that help you write apps that will make users more productive. We'll build off the experience of the morning session and create apps that can save files to the device or iCloud, and exchange them with other apps on the device. We'll also look at some of the other options for persisting data, and exchanging it via copy-and-paste.
But no device is an island, so we'll also introduce some of the ways iOS apps can exchange data with the internet, from opening URLs to sending mail and Tweets.
Attendees will need the latest version of XCode from the Mac App Store. For the iCloud example to work, you need to run on the device, which in turn requires membership in Apple's $99/year iOS Developer Program, though we of course welcome attendees who are not in the program to follow along for that portion of the session.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Aloeswood/Lepoardwood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Chris Adamson</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>iOS</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Building-Productive-iOS-6-Apps-Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>54612c18-3ca0-4c93-b468-2d39b1e1ebb7</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Chris-Adamson</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Building Real Time Web Applications</Title>
		<Abstract>Welcome to Web 3.0.  Today, static web sites are considered boring and unhelpful to your users.  Do users need to constantly hit Refresh in order to pull the latest data your application has to offer?  Why not consider taking a real time approach to your web application.  In this session, we'll be guided through the development of a line of business application that attacks the real time problem head on.  In cases where up to date information is key for business decisions, you're doing yourself a disfavor by staying static.  Come learn how to build real time web applications!

The audience will have the following points to take away from the sessions:

- Understanding of what it means to build a real time web application
- Understanding of basic technology available to implement real time web applications
- Understanding of design considerations and techniques for building real time web applications.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Kevin Griffin</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Design/UX</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Building-Real-Time-Web-Applications</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>06b46be4-0a21-4231-b0f6-9e7afc862504</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Kevin-Griffin</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Building Rich User Experiences Without JavaScript Spaghetti</Title>
		<Abstract>Most Javascript is written to glue code and UI together without any thought to design patterns. Over time this leads to piles of Javascript that look nothing like code you&#x2019;d be proud of writing. In this talk we&#x2019;ll look at the rise of software libraries (like Knockout) that can help add structure to your JS. We&#x2019;ll talk about when they help your project, and when they get in the way. We&#x2019;ll also look into how you can easily use the Mediator and Observer patterns in JavaScript to really clean up your code with or without other libraries. As an added bonus we&#x2019;ll talk about using Message Buses to really decouple your JavaScript controls. We'll compare this messaging approach to a shared models approach (like Backbone). I&#x2019;ll explain how we&#x2019;re using these patterns at Facio and how you can implement them in your code. At the end we'll look at some code samples and we'll talk about whatever other patterns you might be interested in doing in JavaScript.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jared Faris</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Building-Rich-User-Experiences-Without-JavaScript-Spaghetti</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>a38d24b0-fd72-40ef-ba90-daa756e40155</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jared-Faris</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Building WordPress Themes and Plugins--CANCELLED</Title>
		<Abstract>This workshop has been cancelled.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Dave Donaldson</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Wordpress</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Building-WordPress-Themes-and-PluginsCANCELLED</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>074d40f2-b35f-47a5-8400-829ffb72d545</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Dave-Donaldson</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Building, Deploying, and Scaling MongoDB (Tuesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>MongoDB is an open source, document-oriented database designed with scalability and developer agility in mind. MongoDB bridges the gap between key-value stores &#x2013; which are fast and scalable &#x2013; and relational databases &#x2013; which have rich functionality. Instead of storing data in tables and rows as one would with a relational database, MongoDB stores JSON documents with dynamic schemas. This flexible data model makes it easy to use MongoDB and to adapt the database seamlessly as applications evolve.

This workshop will provide an overview of MongoDB and its core capabilities. Coming out of the workshop, participants will have the tools they need to begin developing on MongoDB. The first section, &#x201C;Building your First App with MongoDB,&#x201D; covers the basics of MongoDB's document-oriented model, query language, map-reduce framework and deployment architecture. Next, in &#x201C;Schema Design and Indexing,&#x201D; we will address how to best model your data with MongoDB. In the third session, &#x201C;Intro. To Replication and Sharding,&#x201D; we will introduce the basic concepts around replica sets and sharding, which provide for high availability and horizontal scalability. In the fourth and final session, &#x201C;Deploying your MongoDB Application,&#x201D; we will show you how to operationalize MongoDB and deploy it on-premise or in the cloud.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Sridhar Nanjundeswaran</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Building-Deploying-and-Scaling-MongoDB-Tuesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>a4946e49-6430-418e-9550-17a152ab51cb</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Sridhar-Nanjundeswaran</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>C# Async Programming Workshop (Wednesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Asynchronous programming is much more than using the async and await keywords. In this workshop, you'll build your asynchronous programming skills by writing asynchronous programs.  In addition to working with the new syntax, you'll learn what problems asynchronous programming addresses in both client and server environments. You'll learn to distinguish between threads and asynchronous models, and why Task.Wait is a code smell. You'll spend the rest of the workshop learning to program with Task&lt;T&gt; and TaskCompletionSource&lt;T&gt; in order to build your asynchronous toolbox. By the end of the session, you'll be productive using async idioms in C#.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Bill Wagner</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/C-Async-Programming-Workshop-Wednesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>c7e84ba2-e11e-49aa-8687-f4a81d25231a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Bill-Wagner</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Camper Van Full of ASP.NET - Packing MVC, Web API, Web Forms, and More Into One App</Title>
		<Abstract>Okay, you've heard that ASP.NET is one big framework of love and kisses, right? And legos. But does it actually all work like that? Can we build one ASP.NET app using MVC, Web Forms, and Web API into one application? Will it kind of work but be a big ball of mud? Or a fearsomely beautiful hydra of untold power? Honestly, I don't know. Come along for the ride. Audience members sitting in the front three rows may be eaten. By the hydra. I mean, we just don't know, do we?</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jon Galloway</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Camper-Van-Full-of-ASPNET--Packing-MVC-Web-API-Web-Forms-and-More-Into-One-App</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>684abe13-b77e-4994-8d96-7532781a1048</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jon-Galloway</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Cartography &amp; Coupons - Introducing iOS6 Passbook &amp; MapKit</Title>
		<Abstract>Map Kit was introduced in iOS 5 to provide access to the Google Maps and Google Earth APIs. In iOS 6, Apple now provides their own maps, as well as an easier way to launch the Maps app and display points of interest. Apps that provide routing information can now register as a routing app and make those services available to the entire system. Passbook is a new technology in iOS 6 to implement support for downloadable passes. This can include coupons, boarding passes, event tickets and discount cards.

Learn how to provide and display directions from your iOS apps, as well as what is involved to leverage Pass Kit for your next app.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Eric Hankinson</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Cartography--Coupons--Introducing-iOS6-Passbook--MapKit</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>706324e2-6155-4d45-bd49-7ce66b2fee2d</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Eric-Hankinson</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Choose Your Own Application - The Mystery of the Single-Page App (Tuesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>The relentless Page Refresh has been delivering its blinding white flash to your users and consuming valuable bandwidth for years. Does your team have the Backbone to Knockout the Page Refresh? You can engage the hubs of SignalR, broadcast with Socket.io, or maybe even Pusher. Will your server stack be up to the challenge? Wield frameworks like Node.js, ASP.NET MVC and WebAPI, or Rails. You will practice hours in the dojo of Heroku, and explore Azure skies to complete all of the paths in this adventure. Can you step outside of your comfort zone and mash some code? Are you up to the challenge?

In this session, you will embark on a &#x201C;Choose Your Own Adventure&#x201D;-style project where you will make decisions as you develop a Single-Page Application. You will make technology choices that include JavaScript or CoffeeScript, Backbone or Knockout, ASP.NET or Rails or Node.js, and Heroku or Azure. When you complete your adventure, you will have a fully-working application built with the technologies of your choosing. The best part is, you can keep coding and recoding until you have not one but many incredible implementations of the Single-Page Application. 

More Info at: ChooseYourOwnApplication.com</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Dennis Burton</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Choose-Your-Own-Application--The-Mystery-of-the-SinglePage-App-Tuesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Brian Genisio</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Brian Genisio is a passionate software consultant at SRT Solutions in Ann Arbor, MI and an active member of the Midwest software community. For over 12 years, Brian has worked with countless languages and technologies. Currently, he is focusing on web and mobile-based technologies while playing with frameworks such as ASP.NET MVC, Rails, Flex, Node.js, iOS, PhoneGap, Titanium and Backbone.js. He loves to learn new technologies and he also loves to talk about testing philosophies and methodologies. He can talk your ear off. Just humor him. In his spare time, he enjoys being a cooking nerd which includes traditional barbecue, baking bread, brewing beer and making as much as he can from scratch.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>fdffab02-a2fa-4b1d-ad14-29fc3ab8af86</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Dennis-Burton</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>CI for iOS: Do more while you sleep</Title>
		<Abstract>Continuous Integration (CI) can boost your project up a notch. It can make your dev life easier. You may know this from having used a Continuous Integration server on Java, .NET or Ruby projects - it's pretty common, and for good reason. But CI for iOS is still too rare. This talk will discuss how to get started with CI for your iPhone and iPad projects. We'll cover compiling your code, running tests and deploying your app. We'll also survey other tools you can add to your CI environment to get more done while you sleep.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Kevin Munc</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/CI-for-iOS-Do-more-while-you-sleep</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>17c7fc54-2d56-4e5a-91af-b23e61e268fc</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Kevin-Munc</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Client/Server Apps with HTML5, Play, CoffeeScript, and More</Title>
		<Abstract>The web application landscape is rapidly shifting back to a Client/Server architecture. This time around the Client is JavaScript, HTML, and CSS in the browser. The tools and deployment techniques for these types of applications are abundant and fragmented. This session will teach you how to pull together jQuery, LESS, Twitter Bootstrap, and some CoffeeScript to build the Client. The Server could be anything that talks HTTP but this session will use the Play Framework. You will also learn how to deploy Client/Server web apps on the cloud using a Content Delivery Network (Amazon CloudFront) for the Client and a Cloud Application Provider (Heroku) for the Server.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Rosewood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>James Ward</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Java</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/ClientServer-Apps-with-HTML5-Play-CoffeeScript-and-More</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>DM: Always one of our favorite speakers.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>a2258670-f806-440a-8efa-e91daf747dc5</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/James-Ward</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Closing &amp; Raffle</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-11T21:40:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T22:40:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Closing--Raffle</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>74075dad-325e-4b8f-8b0d-bffba9386107</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Cloud Architecture with Windows Azure (REPEAT SESSION! Wednesday AM Half Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>REPEAT OF TUESDAY'S SESSION

Felix Baumgartner jumped from over 128,000 feet to break a world record for sky diving.  An image was posted to a Facebook account after his landing and in 40 minutes it had logged over 216,000 likes, 10,000 comments, and 29,000 shares.
 
The Pottermore website, digital home to one of the world&#x2019;s greatest known Wizards, saw a billion (with a &#x201C;B&#x201D;) page views just two weeks after it launched and was signing up new users at a rate of 25,000 per day.
 
Whether you need this level of instant scalability, or you are simply wanting to be ready for it when your own idea takes off the cloud allows you to create solutions that can scale easily and have high availability, however, these do not come automatically.  You need to know how best to leverage a cloud platform to achieve these capabilities successfully. This workshop focuses on architecture patterns by looking at how the Windows Azure platform and services actually work, then using that knowledge to design solid solutions.  We will start the workshop with an overview of many of the services and features of the Windows Azure Platform to understand what we have to work with, then we will touch on topics such as distributing your solution globally and handling failures (yes, they WILL happen).  Be ready to participate in groups to put your new knowledge to the test!
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Mike Wood</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Cloud</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Cloud-Architecture-with-Windows-Azure-REPEAT-SESSION-Wednesday-AM-Half-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Brent Stineman</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Brent's career has spanned everything from mainframes to mobile devices. However over the last few years he has focused on distributed and internet based systems. In 2009, he began to focused on cloud computing with the Windows Azure platform. This led to his selection as an inaugural Microsoft MVP for the platform and his eventually joining Microsoft as a Technical Evangelist. The only thing he enjoys more than sharing his passion for cloud with others is what he learns from them in the process.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>4be1efc8-550b-4562-bc62-f6217eaead41</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Mike-Wood</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Cloud Architecture with Windows Azure (Tuesday AM Half Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>Felix Baumgartner jumped from over 128,000 feet to break a world record for sky diving.  An image was posted to a Facebook account after his landing and in 40 minutes it had logged over 216,000 likes, 10,000 comments, and 29,000 shares.
 
The Pottermore website, digital home to one of the world&#x2019;s greatest known Wizards, saw a billion (with a &#x201C;B&#x201D;) page views just two weeks after it launched and was signing up new users at a rate of 25,000 per day.
 
Whether you need this level of instant scalability, or you are simply wanting to be ready for it when your own idea takes off the cloud allows you to create solutions that can scale easily and have high availability, however, these do not come automatically.  You need to know how best to leverage a cloud platform to achieve these capabilities successfully. This workshop focuses on architecture patterns by looking at how the Windows Azure platform and services actually work, then using that knowledge to design solid solutions.  We will start the workshop with an overview of many of the services and features of the Windows Azure Platform to understand what we have to work with, then we will touch on topics such as distributing your solution globally and handling failures (yes, they WILL happen).  Be ready to participate in groups to put your new knowledge to the test!

NOTE: THIS SESSION WILL REPEAT WEDNESDAY MORNING</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Indigo</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Mike Wood</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Cloud</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Cloud-Architecture-with-Windows-Azure-Tuesday-AM-Half-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Brent Stineman</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Brent's career has spanned everything from mainframes to mobile devices. However over the last few years he has focused on distributed and internet based systems. In 2009, he began to focused on cloud computing with the Windows Azure platform. This led to his selection as an inaugural Microsoft MVP for the platform and his eventually joining Microsoft as a Technical Evangelist. The only thing he enjoys more than sharing his passion for cloud with others is what he learns from them in the process.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>f6c7ac55-d73f-489b-bf5d-4ee3cc2b6568</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Mike-Wood</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>CoffeeScript: Good, Bold, and with Sugar</Title>
		<Abstract>CoffeeScript has quickly become one of the most watched projects on GitHub. In this session we will talk about what CoffeeScript is, why it's important, and how it can help you develop better web apps in less time. This little language has taken the web development world by storm and it is gaining converts daily. You'll see how CoffeeScript makes code more readable, how it removes many of the "Bad Parts" of JavaScript, and how it allows you to express yourself more clearly without having to throw out all of the JavaScript skills that you have spent years perfecting. If you develop web applications, you owe it to yourself to learn about CoffeeScript and see if it is right for you.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Daniel Mohl</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/CoffeeScript-Good-Bold-and-with-Sugar</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>f13719fe-7cfd-48a6-bd76-916c8f9ea904</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Daniel-Mohl</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Completely Modern GWT</Title>
		<Abstract>GWT has changed a lot over the years, and sometimes it is good to make a clean break from the past. In this presentation we will examine legacy-free GWT development.
We will cover:

1. In browser and production debugging with Source Maps and SuperDevMode
2. MVP application structure
3. Request Builder and multi-platform messaging
4. Elemental, the new to-the-metal API for WebKit/HTML5 based development.
5. PlayN, the Google Multi-Platform game development suite
6. What is next?</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Robert Cooper</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Java</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Completely-Modern-GWT</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>709e99b7-653e-4641-bbab-b7d4f34eb412</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Robert-Cooper</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Compute Faster with the GPU in C#</Title>
		<Abstract>We all know the GPU can be thousands of times faster than the CPU. Yet few of take the trouble to learn yet another obscure language just to gain a few clock ticks. If you think it would be nice if we could just write code in C# and have it run on the GPU, then this talk is for you. Join us as we write code from scratch to run on either the CPU or GPU. We will cover how to install and use Cudafy, pass data to and from the GPU and upload methods to run on the GPU&#x2019;s massively parallel architecture. After this talk, the shroud of mystery preventing you from using the GPU will have been lifted.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Evan Hauck</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Compute-Faster-with-the-GPU-in-C</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>John Hauck</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>John Hauck has been developing software professionally in Michigan since 1981, and focused on Windows-based development since 1988. For the past 17 years John has been working at LECO, a scientific laboratory instrument company, where he manages software development. John also served as the manager of software development at Zenith Data Systems, and as the Vice President of software development at TechSmith. John loves the Lord, his wife, their three kids, and sailing on Lake Michigan.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>fd54edff-9721-480b-a98b-dd8a39705d72</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Evan-Hauck</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Conjunction Junction! What's Your function()!?</Title>
		<Abstract>An Entire Session on functions in JavaScript. Yep, you heard right, an hour full of bad jokes, horrible puns, internet memes, and completely unrelated references to school house rock. Oh and of course JavaScript. Join us on a magical journey from beginner to advanced to WTF (Whats that Function?!?). Along the way we will make super ultimate friends with hoisting, overloading, recursion, declaration, &#x201C;type&#x201D;, length, arguments, invocation and more. You&#x2019;ve got a fever, and the only prescription is more functions!</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Ryan Rauh</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Conjunction-Junction-Whats-Your-function</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>dc409805-61e0-452c-8190-f67bc27e493e</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Ryan-Rauh</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Connecting to the Outside World</Title>
		<Abstract>Because of Android's open nature, it makes it much easier for Android phone and tablets to connect to external devices via USB, Bluetooth and RS-232 serial interfaces. In this session, we show how to connect an Android tablet to different hardware, such as a barcode reader and a credit card reader via an Arduino board.

We'll look at the tools and techniques you can employ to make connecting to external devices and what pitfalls you may encounter along the way. We'll also write an Android app to read the barcode information and display the data on an Android tablet.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Godfrey Nolan</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Connecting-to-the-Outside-World</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>f1b029d9-0fd3-4c70-b281-1fdb14836a45</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Godfrey-Nolan</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Controlling Precision Electric Motors</Title>
		<Abstract>So you want to build a computer controlled device and toy motors just won&#x2019;t cut it. It might be that you want to add motors to your telescope, build a model cable car with realistic acceleration, or add smooth precision motion to your parade float. If you want to graduate to industrial grade (and reasonably priced) small motor programming, then this talk is for you. We will dive deep into controlling intelligent stepper motor by tuning accelerations, experimenting with position accuracy, developing a homing sequence, adjusting run currents, and implementing dynamic position maintenance. After this talk, you will see the world of movement just waiting to be automated. The presenter has written code for many automation systems.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon G</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>John Michael Hauck</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Hardware</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Controlling-Precision-Electric-Motors</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>819d3587-e055-4ea1-86da-f604de9b2d42</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/John-Michael-Hauck</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Controlling Your Robot Army with C#, Netduino and Kinect </Title>
		<Abstract>Brian and Stephen (father and son) have spent the last five years off and on working with Robotics and Electronics. Stephen started with Lego Mindstorms, got deeper into electronics with SnapCircuits and the Parallax Basic Stamp and finally convinced his dad that Arduino was the next big thing. As a .Net developer, Brian joined in with the Netduino platform and C#. Together, they have explored electronics and robotics with the goal of creating a remote control robot with .Net and Kinect. They will be bringing their current robot project and showing steps/missteps along the way.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon G</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Brian Sherwin</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Hardware</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Controlling-Your-Robot-Army-with-C-Netduino-and-Kinect-</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Stephen Sherwin</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Stephen is 14 and has already wowed an audience with his Resharper skills. He is homeschooled but in his spare time, he loves reading, science stuff and backyard ballistics. He enjoys Scouting and is currently a Life Scout.
</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>0e45f1e1-3256-45a9-a59f-64b4e3e330c9</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Brian-Sherwin</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Convenience vs. Security (Wednesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Technology is great! It makes our life easier! More and more our devices seamlessly connect and things "just work"&#x2026; but sometimes there is a dark side to this functionality. What assumptions are made to enable the seamlessness that we crave? What tradeoffs are occurring that we might not even be aware of?
 
During this session Bill and Rob walk through a number of widely used technologies and platforms and discuss/demonstrate the weaknesses that are present in them. We begin by dealing with the ubiquitous WiFi and deal both with access point and client side attacks and weaknesses.  We then move on and demonstrate how easy it is to fall prey to phishing and spear phishing attacks.  For those of you who feel safe due to your exceptional computer practices and prowess - we talk about and demonstrate "water cooler" attacks.
 
This session ends by dealing with how to protect yourself once the bad guys are "in" (an assumption that the first part of the session will give you an appreciation for).  How do you keep your site's user info from being the next big thing on PasteBin? How do you keep your name out of the news? What best practices should you be implementing now to make yourself (and the platforms you are responsible for) more secure?
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Ironwood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Rob Gillen</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Security</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Convenience-vs-Security-Wednesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Bill Sempf</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Bill Sempf is a software architect.  His breadth of experience includes business and technical analysis, software design, development, testing, server management and maintenance, and security.  In his 17 years of professional experience he has participated in the creation of well over 200 applications for large and small companies, managed the software infrastructure of two Internet service providers, coded complex software happily in every environment imaginable, and made mainframes talk to cell phones. 
 
He is the author of C# 2010 All in One for Dummies; a coauthor of Effective Visual Studio.NET and many other books, a frequent contributor to industry magazines; and has recently been an invited speaker for the ACM and IEEE, CodeMash, DerbyCon, BSides, DevEssentials, the International XML Web Services Expo and the Association of Information Technology Professionals. Bill also serves on the board of the Columbus branch of the Open Web Application Security Project, and is the Administrative Director of Locksport International.
</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>3f7bee7e-5669-4267-99db-02d3b53b76b1</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Rob-Gillen</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Crash Course in Windows 8 </Title>
		<Abstract>An intensive introduction to the mindset, style and coding of Windows 8.  Topics covered include Layout, Interaction, Navigation, Async programming, Presenting Data, Native to XAML, Native to HTML, What .NET Developers need to know, more.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Aloeswood/Leopardswood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jesse Liberty</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Windows 8</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Crash-Course-in-Windows-8-</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>09ed1a72-41cf-4626-9cf8-527bc84b733e</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jesse-Liberty</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Crash Course in Windows 8 - Beyond the Basics</Title>
		<Abstract>Advanced topics in programming for Windows 8 with XAML and C#.  Topics include Asynchronous programming, Tiles, Toast and Notification, Contracts, Searching, Sharing, Location and more</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Aloeswood/Leopardswood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jesse Liberty</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Windows 8</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Crash-Course-in-Windows-8--Beyond-the-Basics</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>805aca3f-ebfa-442d-aa67-f9445620528e</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jesse-Liberty</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Creative Problem Solving - REPEAT SESSION - (Wednesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>(Limited to 40 participants each) 
In today&#x2019;s demanding market, when every effort is maximized and any improvement counts, creativity can become your winning edge.The importance of creative mind in the corporate world cannot be emphasized enough. During this workshop, you will deepen your core skills in collaboration, creativity, empathy, and problem solving. This original workshop will open the door to the hidden creativity potential within you.  Building on proven applied improvisational techniques and principles, in a fun and supportive environment, we will show you how to change routine patterns, step outside your comfort zone, and fuel new ideas.  

We will focus on the following topics:
Looking at ideas and issues from multiple perspectives and challenging assumptions
Using the &#x201C;yes, and&#x2026;&#x201D; principle as a key to a successful teamwork 
Learning how to shift in the moment and be flexible with your agenda
Stepping outside your comfort zone in a trusting environment
Thinking on the spot
Tapping into your creative side
Building active listening skills</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jessie Shternshus </SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Communication</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Creative-Problem-Solving--REPEAT-SESSION--Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>e30b72a5-495f-47e5-8999-8264cb5751f6</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jessie-Shternshus-</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Creative Problem Solving (Wednesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>(Limited to 40 participants each) 
In today&#x2019;s demanding market, when every effort is maximized and any improvement counts, creativity can become your winning edge.The importance of creative mind in the corporate world cannot be emphasized enough. During this workshop, you will deepen your core skills in collaboration, creativity, empathy, and problem solving. This original workshop will open the door to the hidden creativity potential within you.  Building on proven applied improvisational techniques and principles, in a fun and supportive environment, we will show you how to change routine patterns, step outside your comfort zone, and fuel new ideas.  

We will focus on the following topics:
Looking at ideas and issues from multiple perspectives and challenging assumptions
Using the &#x201C;yes, and&#x2026;&#x201D; principle as a key to a successful teamwork 
Learning how to shift in the moment and be flexible with your agenda
Stepping outside your comfort zone in a trusting environment
Thinking on the spot
Tapping into your creative side
Building active listening skills
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jessie Shternshus </SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Communication</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Creative-Problem-Solving-Wednesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>1ba51652-d9bc-4909-96b5-7648e9f87890</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jessie-Shternshus-</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dataflow Programming on Big Data with Scalding, a Scala DSL</Title>
		<Abstract>How does Twitter know what topics are trending, or what movies people are liking in Sandusky? Cascading is a Java project designed to provide a dataflow programming model with a runtime that can scale across thousands of machines and is used in companies like Twitter, Etsy and Razorfish to perform analysis on large sets of data.  We will get started by running Cascading on a single node for simple analysis, and then scale to a large Hadoop cluster running in Windows Azure.  We will perform more complex analytics using Scalding, a DSL for Scala that allows you to do a lot of work with a little bit code on a lot of data. 
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Matt Winkler</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Scala</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dataflow-Programming-on-Big-Data-with-Scalding-a-Scala-DSL</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>3afe45b3-2354-4bbe-a7bc-c4bb3b6ef0cc</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Matt-Winkler</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Design For Developers: Why Windows 8 Will Make You Creative</Title>
		<Abstract>In today's development world, being a great coder isn't enough anymore.  You've got to start thinking about user experience just as much as you do architecture.  This talk will walk you through how Windows 8 development will make you a better developer by forcing you to think about design.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Aloeswood/Leopardswood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jeff Blankenburg</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Windows 8</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Design-For-Developers-Why-Windows-8-Will-Make-You-Creative</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>a583a4c0-8c3b-417f-8be1-4c580d7695a4</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jeff-Blankenburg</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Developing for the Android (Wednesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Creating a mobile strategy is something many companies still struggle with. iOS and Android own the majority of market share for smartphones, so Android will play a big part in any good mobile strategy. The Android SDK has matured in the more than four years since the first release, and the strong Android community has different opinions among many developers. In this session, Jeff and Scott will work with you to develop an Android application, from start to publish. The majority of this talk will discuss native Android development using Java, but will finish with a few alternatives.  They will provide the training for you to leave this talk ready to turn &#x201C;I have an idea&#x201D; into &#x201C;you should see this app.&#x201D;

There is no Java prerequisite for this session, and we will work with you to ensure a great learning experience. But we do ask that you come prepared, installing the Android Development tools on your laptop. Please visit http://www.gravityworksdesign.com/About/SpeakingEvents/AndroidPrecompiler.aspx for detailed instructions before the session.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jeff McWherter</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Android</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Developing-for-the-Android-Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Scott Gowell</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Jeff McWherter and Scott Gowell work together at Gravity Works Design &amp; Development, a consulting shop in Lansing, Michigan founded on a passion for detail-focused design, sound development practices,education, and community involvement. Over the last three years, Jeff and Scott have been pairing together to deliver both web and mobile applications to a wide range of clients, including U2, Molly Maid, Mr. Handy Man and the Michigan High School Athletic Association. If a problem exists they have seen it; with a combined total of over 29 years of professional software consulting experience. Working together to push the envelope of mobile development, they have learned to love new versions of the Android SDK.  They worked with just about every mobile framework out there, and will be able to answer specific questions about your mobile development needs. In 2012 they released Professional Mobile Application Development, published by Wrox. </SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>549f8104-af0a-480f-8154-0e77c8b11988</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jeff-McWherter</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Developing Mobile applications with PhoneGap (Tuesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>The free and open source Cordova framework is a powerful tool that enables developers to re-use their existing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript skills to create powerful, rich mobile applications. In this hands on session, Raymond will give attendees an introduction to the framework and it's features. A discussion of web standards, with a focus on mobile support, will cover HTML5 and CSS3 topics. Next, the class will begin creating their own applications making use of the Ripple emulator as well as the PhoneGap Build service.

Students should have basic HTML knowledge as well as a handle on the basics of JavaScript.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Ray Camden</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Developing-Mobile-applications-with-PhoneGap-Tuesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>48a217f8-7ada-47a0-80f8-7116e9dc29be</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Ray-Camden</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Developing on Windows 8 (Tuesday Full Day) </Title>
		<Abstract>Windows 8 is Windows re-imagined, representing today&#x2019;s single biggest opportunity for developers.  Join us for a Windows 8 app workshop to learn how you can take full advantage.  You'll learn from experts in a low-key, interactive way and then get hands-on time to apply what you&#x2019;ve learned.

In this workshop you will gain an understanding of the platform design tenets, the programming language choices, and the integration points with the operating system and across Windows Store apps.  You'll learn the design principles behind the Windows Store apps and get insights into how to apply these principles in your own apps.  We'll cover updates to familiar .NET or Silverlight features and explore concepts that are new for Windows 8 and show you how to turn your XAML skills into money-making Windows Store apps.

Windows 8 provides a new ready-to-use set of user interface controls and we'll show you how to use them to implement the common patterns that deliver great Windows 8 Store apps.  We'll teach you how to design adaptive layouts that ensure that your apps look great across all different screen sizes, resolutions and aspect ratios
 
With Windows 8 you'll design your app with the expectation that touch will be the primary input method of your users. Support for mouse and pen/stylus requires no additional work as Windows 8 provides this for free. We'll teach you about the touch language and patterns as well as how to incorporate mouse, keyboard and pen. You&#x2019;ll also learn about the techniques to use for direct manipulation, such as touch targets, layout, margins and use of app bars.
 
Your app's Tiles and Notifications keep it front and center increasing the connection with the user.  In this session we'll cover how you can include primary and secondary Tiles that are "live" encouraging the user to personalize their Start screen by pinning info from your app.
 
Windows Store apps use contracts to declare the interactions that they support with other apps.  We'll teach you how to design apps that implement contracts to attract new users or delight existing users by providing them seamless integration with other apps or the system.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Ben Riga</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Windows 8</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Developing-on-Windows-8-Tuesday-Full-Day-</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Peter Dwersteg</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Peter Dwersteg is a Windows 8 Evangelist at Microsoft. He is a graduate of the University of Washington, and has previously worked in computer science education at the university level, as well as working in Storage and File Systems for Windows 8. In his free time he enjoys soccer and living all the adventures life can offer.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>c5a41284-b8bc-4699-8c52-f80470c9ef0a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Ben-Riga</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dinner - Thursday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-10T23:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T00:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dinner--Thursday</URI>
		<EventType>Meal</EventType>
		<Id>70bf97c0-0c7f-436b-950a-02dffefcd11a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dojo: Ball Flow Challenge</Title>
		<Abstract>Get up and get agile! The Ball Flow Challenge is an interactive puzzle that gets participants out of their seats to learn/reinforce agile concepts. Great for people of all agile skill levels.

The Dojo is a place where you can go to practice your craft, hone your skills, and learn from others. Each session will have a featured kata or other hands-on activity.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T19:45:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Telerik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Agile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dojo-Ball-Flow-Challenge</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>3203e722-5149-428d-80c2-a0936d750045</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Telerik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dojo: Designing with C.R.A.P.</Title>
		<Abstract>Does your app look like crap? Good news: you can tame it with four easy-to-learn design principles, no BFA required.

The Dojo is a place where you can go to practice your craft, hone your skills, and learn from others. Each session will have a featured kata or other hands-on activity. 

You&#x2019;re encouraged to bring a laptop so you can participate in the hands-on portion.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T15:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Telerik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Design/UX</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dojo-Designing-with-CRAP</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>f4c56bac-d19a-4929-a6f2-24e76a59d0b6</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Telerik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dojo: Gilded Rose Kata</Title>
		<Abstract>The Gilded Rose Inn's inventory system developer has moved on to new adventures. Do you have what it takes to add a new feature that allows the inn to sell a new category of items?

The Dojo is a place where you can go to practice your craft, hone your skills, and learn from others. Each session will have a featured kata or other hands-on activity. 

You&#x2019;re encouraged to bring a laptop with your preferred development tools, but it&#x2019;s not necessary as we encourage pairing.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T16:45:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Telerik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dojo-Gilded-Rose-Kata</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>a1237068-84fb-498a-b69c-742bb9708cd5</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Telerik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dojo: Greed Kata</Title>
		<Abstract>Greed is a press-your-luck dice rolling game where the roller tries to earn as many points as possible.

The Dojo is a place where you can go to practice your craft, hone your skills, and learn from others. Each session will have a featured kata or other hands-on activity. 

You&#x2019;re encouraged to bring a laptop with your preferred development tools, but it&#x2019;s not necessary as we encourage pairing.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T17:00:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Telerik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dojo-Greed-Kata</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>51eaf180-5e96-4683-973e-0d73ef6fcff0</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Telerik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dojo: Intro to Typography - Bingo Edition</Title>
		<Abstract>Typography lingo doesn't have to sound like a foreign language. Members of Telerik's Services design team will be breaking it down in this interactive Dojo session. Come to learn the basics, stay to play a game of BINGO!

The Dojo is a place where you can go to practice your craft, hone your skills, and learn from others. Each session will have a featured kata or other hands-on activity. </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T21:45:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Telerik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Design/UX</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dojo-Intro-to-Typography--Bingo-Edition</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>44fc4971-0aa0-499d-9eeb-38b19a0845bd</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Telerik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dojo: Marshmallow Challenge</Title>
		<Abstract>The task is simple: in 18 minutes, teams must build the tallest free-standing structure out of 20 sticks of spaghetti, 1 yard of tape, 1 yard of string, and 1 marshmallow. The marshmallow needs to be on top. Do you have what it takes?

The Dojo is a place where you can go to practice your craft, hone your skills, and learn from others. Each session will have a featured kata or other hands-on activity.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T19:45:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Telerik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Agile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dojo-Marshmallow-Challenge</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>5c1b1fdf-36d0-4e8f-a35f-d79683c5ec7b</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Telerik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dojo: Potter Kata</Title>
		<Abstract>In this kata we'll calculate the optimal discount for customers buying the Harry Potter book series. Wands are permitted, but not required.

The Dojo is a place where you can go to practice your craft, hone your skills, and learn from others. Each session will have a featured kata or other hands-on activity. 

You&#x2019;re encouraged to bring a laptop with your preferred development tools, but it&#x2019;s not necessary as we encourage pairing.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T21:35:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Telerik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dojo-Potter-Kata</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>eb99ecb6-6c42-4f70-afc2-3a617d796cc1</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Telerik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dojo: String Calculator Kata</Title>
		<Abstract>This kata was created by Roy Osherove and is designed to help you learn test-first coding and refactoring. 

The Dojo is a place where you can go to practice your craft, hone your skills, and learn from others. Each session will have a featured kata or other hands-on activity. 

You&#x2019;re encouraged to bring a laptop with your preferred development tools, but it&#x2019;s not necessary as we encourage pairing.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T22:50:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Telerik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dojo-String-Calculator-Kata</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>996d8a73-669d-48c5-9ea6-15d5faceae5f</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Telerik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Dojo: Urinal Kata</Title>
		<Abstract>This session will feature the Urinal Kata from Mel Grubb's Pecha Kucha talk at last year's CodeMash. In fact, Mel will be in the Dojo to kick off this session by giving his talk again. So if you missed his hilarious talk last year, here's your chance to catch it. 

The Dojo is a place where you can go to practice your craft, hone your skills, and learn from others. Each session will have a featured kata or other hands-on activity. 

You&#x2019;re encouraged to bring a laptop with your preferred development tools, but it&#x2019;s not necessary as we encourage pairing.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T15:45:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Telerik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dojo-Urinal-Kata</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>89862a33-827e-4a74-992e-127d6a70a4cd</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Telerik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Don't develop prototypes...Sketchflow them</Title>
		<Abstract>In a world of knee jerk reactions by management and clients showing a working prototype can be a killer.  They either love the way it looks without thinking about its functionality or hate the way it looks without ever focusing on the functionality.  Either way they miss the goal that prototyping should accomplish.  In walks Sketchflow to save you.  This tool provides a great way to create a functional prototype while purposely avoiding the look/feel barrier.  It also provides a great way to send out the prototype to remote users and capture their feedback on a view by view basis.  We'll look at the basics of creating a Sketchflow prototype and also examine the tool for getting feedback.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jonathan Small</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Design/UX</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Dont-develop-prototypesSketchflow-them</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>9a04a2d5-ed53-4011-8b1c-a1155139003a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jonathan-Small</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>DON'T PANIC: The Hitchhiker's Guide to Debugging</Title>
		<Abstract>Debugging techniques are about the most massively useful things an interstellar hitchhiker/developer can have... anyone who can debug code is clearly a person to be reckoned with and a hoopy frood indeed.

At the end of this talk, you will have the knowledge about debugging techniques that can be used throughout the stack such as:

* Reading error messages and stack traces: There&#x2019;s no point in acting surprised about it. All the information has been on display in your terminal for minutes now, why didn't you go look at it?

* Narrowing down the possibilities: Create a reverse Total Perspective Vortex. Start from every possible piece of matter in the universe and trace the effects back to the piece of fairy cake that caused everything.

* Writing tests: both to find the problem and to prevent cases of "Oh no, not again!"</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Carol Nichols</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Software Process</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/DONT-PANIC-The-Hitchhikers-Guide-to-Debugging</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Jake Goulding</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Jake loves knowing as much as possible about **why** something works, not just **how**. He's a passionate advocate for always improving code and processes. He tweets @JakeGoulding and blogs at jakegoulding.com. His least favorite error is Error 1.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>d025f732-ced3-4f9b-a915-1f9f82e53394</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Carol-Nichols</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Effective Actors</Title>
		<Abstract>There are several frameworks across languages and platforms of Actors, including Erlang, Fantom, Java and Scala. As developers have built systems using these frameworks, patterns of use have begun to emerge that represent "Best Practices" for actor-based systems. In this talk, we will review such patterns, focusing primarily on how to implement them using the Akka framework and Scala.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Indigo Bay</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jamie Allen</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Scala</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Effective-Actors</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>738c3e13-d220-4a87-90eb-d1e0c09ebfd3</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jamie-Allen</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Emergent Architecture with TDD/BDD</Title>
		<Abstract>As architects, we have all experienced the folly of BDUF (Big Design Up Front) &#x2013; spending weeks or months perfecting an architecture that fails when it meets the real requirements and real code. Is it possible to design in the small? How can we avoid unintended complexity, which cripples so many code bases? Can we build enough of an architecture to start writing code and then flesh out our architecture as the code evolves? In this session we examine how Test-Driven Development (TDD) and Behaviour-Driven Development (BDD) allow us to solve these conundrums. We will see how we can use TDD/BDD to focus our architectural efforts in the high-value areas of our code base to achieve just-in-time architecture.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>James Kovacs</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Emergent-Architecture-with-TDDBDD</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>b03db4f9-2fca-4850-a44b-3a533baa47dd</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/James-Kovacs</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Essential Cocoa Networking</Title>
		<Abstract>This presentation covers the most common things apps will do with the network: fetching resources and interacting with web services over HTTP(S). We'll start with NSURLConnection, explore third-party APIs that wrap and extend it, and finish up with tips on how you can optimize your use of the network for speed and battery life.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Steve Madsen</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Essential-Cocoa-Networking</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>61716fb2-ad2e-4aa0-bd12-d1708c792dab</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Steve-Madsen</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Families: Dinner Meet-up</Title>
		<Abstract>CodeMash Families Meet-up for dinner @ The Reserve (Wear your name badge so we can find you!)</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>The Reserve</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Families-Dinner-Meetup</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>745b8a15-d47a-4dc3-928a-5cb7d3527f23</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Families: Game Night</Title>
		<Abstract>CodeMash Families Game Night Extravaganza</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T01:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Acacia</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Families-Game-Night</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>0880bf7f-2cb4-4f84-90ca-a8c9bfbdb432</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Families: Momz (Spouse&#x2019;s) Night Out</Title>
		<Abstract>CodeMash Families Momz (Spouse&#x2019;s) Night Out: Cocktail Hour</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-12T01:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Ivory Coast Lounge</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Families-Momz-Spouses-Night-Out</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>ccdaecfa-dd7f-43f0-9ac6-a3e3371f0adc</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Families: Movie Night</Title>
		<Abstract>CodeMash Families Movie Night w/snacks</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T01:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Acacia</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Families-Movie-Night</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>208fd18c-9591-4f85-a6b9-2d4b4932743e</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Families: Up All Night</Title>
		<Abstract>CodeMash Families &#x201C;Up All Night&#x201D; Water Park Meet-Up CMF Cabana</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T04:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>CMF Cabana</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Families-Up-All-Night</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>f88e3281-3d7a-4281-8d91-b7cb4315b547</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Full Stack Integration Tests with Node.js</Title>
		<Abstract>Writing full-stack integration tests can be a time consuming and tedious process in any language.  As your application grows, your tests naturally should take longer and longer to run and become more difficult to maintain.  Using node you can actually dramatically increasing the speed of your tests and still achieve the same level of test coverage.  Specifically I'll show you how you can use Zombie.js or Phantom.js and Cucumber.js to perform integration tests on your application.  We'll also take a look at some useful tools for things like mock objects and JSON factories and some common pitfalls you can avoid.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Rosewood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Mike Swift</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Full-Stack-Integration-Tests-with-Nodejs</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>efecd52e-01c9-40b4-a774-333c477c90f0</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Mike-Swift</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Fully Operational FubuMVC 1.0 (Wednesday Half Day, PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>FubuMVC has quietly been in active use and development for a little over three years as a web development framework for .Net, but now it&#x2019;s time for its full coming-out party.  Even if you&#x2019;re perfectly happy with the framework your team uses, FubuMVC incorporates some ideas and features not found in today&#x2019;s most popular frameworks such as Ruby on Rails or ASP.Net MVC.
We&#x2019;ll start things off by showing how to start a minimalistic project with FubuMVC and do all the basic &#x201C;Hello World&#x201D; operations that every web framework does without breaking a sweat, but focus on how the FubuMVC &#x201C;one model in, one model out&#x201D; approach is different.  We&#x2019;ll quickly follow that up by showing many of the features we believe are unique to FubuMVC like composable Html conventions, Url resolution logic, integrated authorization, and &#x201C;meta-conventions.&#x201D; 
FubuMVC relies very heavily on conventions for developer productivity as opposed to explicit directives like a Sinatra-flavored tool or higher ceremony tools like ASP.Net MVC.  We strongly prefer that approach because of how clean the code becomes, but that kind of &#x201C;black magic&#x201D; can easily cause just as much harm as good.  Fortunately the FubuMVC team has made a deep investment in diagnostics to explain the conventions that are active in your system, how they impact the behavior of your system, and full runtime tracing to visualize how an http request is handled by the various runtime parts of your FubuMVC application.  We&#x2019;ll show you how to use the FubuMVC.Diagnostics package to understand and troubleshoot problems with your FubuMVC project.
FubuMVC supports a very rich modularity story using the related Bottles library and a relentless focus on composing code in an &#x201C;open/closed&#x201D; fashion.  In this session we&#x2019;ll quickly assemble a simple application by dropping in several off the shelf Bottles to handle infrastructure concerns like authentication and validation and even simplify usage of JavaScript assets like Twitter Bootstrap and jQuery.UI.  We&#x2019;ll also show you how to build your own Bottles &#x2013; both for reusable infrastructure concerns and how to isolate features into their own Bottle projects to facilitate Continuous Deployment strategies.
FubuMVC also comes with a very powerful asset pipeline to fully control script and stylesheet loading, dependencies between assets, caching policies, and a transformation pipeline for minification, combining assets, and using languages like CoffeeScript, LeSS, and Sass.  We&#x2019;ll show you how to use the asset pipeline in development and talk about the steps we&#x2019;ve taken to improve performance and smooth out the development process.  We&#x2019;ll also show you how to incorporate Html templates generated on the server as assets for &#x201C;Single Page Application&#x201D; style development.
Time permitting, we&#x2019;ll also show how we do automated testing against FubuMVC applications at the unit test, integration testing with the Kayak web server, and acceptance testing using WebDriver.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jeremy Miller</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Fully-Operational-FubuMVC-10-Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Josh Arnold</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Forthcoming</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>10abb979-a25b-436e-809c-c5e85eaa6269</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jeremy-Miller</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Functional Testing with ASP.NET MVC</Title>
		<Abstract>You unit test, even integration test your application. You get to 100% code coverage, but when you finally deploy your application, the system is broken! How can we have full code coverage, but our application still breaks?
In this session, we'll look at functional testing with ASP.NET MVC and how we can design our system for testability. We'll also look at how we can write functional tests that don't break easily, and see how we can finally ditch the test recorders.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jimmy Bogard</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Functional-Testing-with-ASPNET-MVC</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>88afcbfd-62b0-47ac-98aa-f1d09e3e2f73</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jimmy-Bogard</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Gamification of our World</Title>
		<Abstract>Brian freely admits that he will do anything for an achievement on his Xbox; after all he has four of them at home. One day Brian wondered if he could get achievements for just putting on pants going to this place called &#x2018;outside.&#x2019; This thinking has led to the gamification of our world, where achievements, game design elements, and game theory have leapt from gaming across the wall to everyday life. Learn the how&#x2019;s and why of gamification. Everyone is using it to build wanted behavior, from enterprise developer teams, to sales teams, and to kids with diabetes. Being a gamer is not required, but we can&#x2019;t guarantee you won&#x2019;t become one when you are done.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Indigo Bay</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Brian Prince</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Game Development</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Gamification-of-our-World</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>0db8718a-3cef-46f4-b7be-e7c0a0aa1303</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Brian-Prince</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Gesture Recognition with Kinect for Windows</Title>
		<Abstract>Developer and co-host of .NET Rocks!, Carl Franklin shows you
how to go about recognizing gestures with K4Win based on his work with GesturePak, a "Gesture Recording and Recognition Toolkit." GesturePak records you making gestures and then notifies your app when your user has made one or more of those gestures.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Aloeswood/Leopardswood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Carl Franklin</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Gesture-Recognition-with-Kinect-for-Windows</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>4aa3df35-b70d-42ce-8af6-19d50d02a9f1</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Carl-Franklin</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Getting Good: How to Integrate Novice Developers into Your Team</Title>
		<Abstract>Good developer talent is extremely hard to find. If you need to scale your team, what options do you have? LivingSocial took an unconventional route and brought on 24 ruby novices for an intensive 5-month developer training program. The litmus test of the program comes now that their development careers have started. How will these beginners deliver value? What lessons can be learned about integrating junior developers into existing teams with large amounts of legacy code? 
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Elise Worthy</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Business</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Getting-Good-How-to-Integrate-Novice-Developers-into-Your-Team</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Steve Klabnik</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Steve is a Ruby Hero, software craftsman, and an aspiring digital humanities scholar. He spends most of his time contributing to Open Source projects, and maintains both Hackety Hack and Shoes. He also teaches classes with Jumpstart Lab.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>684fa32a-2a80-40e1-894e-386c97bb888c</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Elise-Worthy</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Getting Mobile with iOS and Windows Azure Mobile Services</Title>
		<Abstract>Ready to build the next great iOS app but don't want to think about the backend? In this session, we&#x2019;ll go over connecting your iOS apps to Windows Azure Mobile Services.  Mobile Services allow your apps to take advantage of easy data storage, user auth with multiple providers, push notifications and more.  When we're done, you'll be ready to create a great cloud connected app!</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Chris Risner</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Getting-Mobile-with-iOS-and-Windows-Azure-Mobile-Services</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>bb597d51-bdcc-4942-9cf9-8edcbc0edd1d</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Chris-Risner</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Go! Go! Go-lang Awesome!</Title>
		<Abstract>The Go language was born out of frustration with existing languages and environments for systems programming. Systems programming had become difficult and the languages available were a big part of the problem. You could choose ease with Python or efficiency with C++ or safety with Java.  None of the choices could address all concerns.

Enter (Rob Pike's Masterwork) the language Go. Go is the space-based I-have-come-from-the-future-to-save-you tactical nuclear smasher-of-evil you have been waiting for. it is a modern language with support for advanced networking, multicore computing, excellent string handling and portability.

No previous experience with Go is required for this introductory talk.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Joshua Smith</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other Languages</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Go-Go-Golang-Awesome</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>0ab1f130-4713-4252-b5f2-27da5579bc49</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Joshua-Smith</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Going Independent (Tuesday Full Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>Breaking free from the confines of the cubicle farm and going out on your own can be one of the most satisfying things you do for your career. It can also be one of the most terrifying. Being on your own can seem like it's nothing but ponies, unicorns and rainbows, but it's a lot of work, and success is not guaranteed.

Mike, an independent developer since 2001, will discuss the lessons he's learned over the years along with the ups and downs he's experienced. In this updated and expanded session, he will be joined by two legal professionals to help answer the most common questions he's been asked over the years. "How do I get started?", "Where do I find clients?", "How much do I charge?", "Do I need a contract?" and many others. Bring your questions and find out if the grass really is greener on the other side.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Ironwood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Mike Eaton</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Going-Independent-Tuesday-Full-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>d2d62530-b7a2-4821-b30c-3324f941c625</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Mike-Eaton</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Hello, Arduino: Write Code that Interacts with the Real World</Title>
		<Abstract>Take the first step in raising your robot army, and meet the Arduino, the microcontroller designed to be approachable and fun. From blinky lights to motors, temperature sensors to wifi, RFID to MIDI, you can make your code DO STUFF. If you are familiar with a curly-brace-and-semi-colon language (JavaScript, C#, Java, C, PHP...), you've already mastered half of the equation. Electronics is the other half, and the Arduino simplifies much of that, too, and gives you a fun platform on which to learn it. In this lively and interactive session, Sharon will introduce you to the Arduino by walking through a series of building-block projects, writing code and plugging bits into breadboards. Seeing the available options and how they come together is sure to get your imagination cranking.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon E</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Sharon Cichelli</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Hardware</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Hello-Arduino-Write-Code-that-Interacts-with-the-Real-World</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>3f8de5e0-5acf-4327-96c6-44ed5814771d</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Sharon-Cichelli</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Hippie Free Backbone: Beyond the To Do List (Wednesday All Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>Have you heard about Backbone and thought single-page applications were unpossible? Do you wonder about the big kerfluffle with Coffeescript? Tired of examples that only show shiny new Backbone.js applications? In two half-day sessions, we'll show you how to leverage these tools to improve an old, busted website that could use a little love. Indeed, there aren't any websites out there like that, but we&#x2019;ll arm you with some tools to change them should you ever encounter the rare case...
The morning session will be all JavaScript, all the time. We'll start by delving into the dark corners of the language, examining the syntax, common practical patterns, and other idiosyncrasies. After our intro to Javascript we'll work on our example app, and turn "pretty good" JavaScript into code that displays separation of concerns and code that is easily testable. We'll use Backbone.js, the Underscore.js tools included with Backbone.js, and the Jasmine testing framework to treat your client-side code like a first class citizen without overhauling your existing application.
The afternoon session will introduce CoffeeScript to those who haven't had much exposure to it. CoffeeScript is a language that complies into JavaScript, and it is baked into newer versions of Ruby on Rails. We'll show some of the syntax and patterns, and we'll explain why someone would want to use it over plain, boring JavaScript. After we get familiar with CoffeeScript, we'll hit the reset button on our example app from the morning session and once again set to refactoring it to be clean, beautiful, well tested code with Backbone.js, but do it all in CoffeeScript this time.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>E</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Tim Wingfield</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Hippie-Free-Backbone-Beyond-the-To-Do-List-Wednesday-All-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Michael Kramer</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Michael Joseph Kramer is a passionate software developer focusing on quality, testing, and agile practices. Michael has over 10 years of experience creating applications on a wide variety of platforms, and he has worked as both an IT professional and a consultant. He is currently an independent consultant at Sage House, LLC specializing in JavaScript, CoffeeScript, Ruby, and Agile Practices. He also recently ran a marathon, and it's now the only thing he ever talks about.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>504abb30-4f2a-4abb-9f24-9ce24d01314d</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Tim-Wingfield</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>How HTML5 Makes YOU a Windows 8 Store App Dev Already!</Title>
		<Abstract>Are you a web developer? Your toolset makes you a Windows 8 Metro app developer because HTML5 is now a first class citizen for making WinRT apps. Using HTML5 along with JavaScript and CSS3, Microsoft has enabled web developers from all platforms the ability to start app dev with a very low learning curve. Come see what that learning curve looks like, as Greg discusses what WinJS is and how to use it. You will learn about the basics of Windows Store App patterns, navigation, async, and operating system integration.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Greg Levenhagen</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Windows 8</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/How-HTML5-Makes-YOU-a-Windows-8-Store-App-Dev-Already</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>e6bbe37a-572d-4d4f-aea0-96b373110d55</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Greg-Levenhagen</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love jQuery</Title>
		<Abstract>JavaScript is an excellent way to add rich client-side functionality to a web site. But differences in the DOM implementation by the various browsers and platforms can make JavaScript difficult. JQuery solves this by providing a library of functions that provide simplified, consistent, cross-browser, cross-platform JavaScript support.
In this session, I will show how to add jQuery to your applications and use it to add rich functionality to your web sites. 
This presentation is heavy on examples, showing jQuery syntax and functionality; showing Ajax calls with jQuery; and showing jQuery UI examples.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>David Giard</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/How-I-Learned-to-Stop-Worrying-and-Love-jQuery</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>8a833c1d-98c8-4cc7-81f6-7d06bc1c3f1a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/David-Giard</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>How it's Made: Behind the scenes of Building Microsoft Roslyn</Title>
		<Abstract>Take a look behind the scenes at the processes that power Microsoft's Roslyn project.  In this overview, we'll cover how the team has taken advantage of agile planning to manage priorities and scheduling.  We'll take a look at the development process including the approach to designing and writing code.  Testing and testability are a huge focus of the Roslyn project, and the team writes several distinct types of automated tests, and employs a variety of other testing techniques. Finally we'll examine some of the unique challenges faced by a project like Roslyn - huge backwards compatibility requirements, hard to meet performance scenarios, and more.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Kevin Pilch-Bisson</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/How-its-Made-Behind-the-scenes-of-Building-Microsoft-Roslyn</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>58b47b5a-f4d9-46b0-8566-fa63c1087d83</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Kevin-PilchBisson</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>How it's made: Behind the scenes of building Microsoft Roslyn (Wednesday Half Day, PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Take a look behind the scenes at the processes that power Microsoft's Roslyn project.  In this overview, we'll cover how the team has taken advantage of agile planning to manage priorities and scheduling.  We'll take a look at the development process including the approach to designing and writing code.  Testing and testability are a huge focus of the Roslyn project, and the team writes several distinct types of automated tests, and employs a variety of other testing techniques. Finally we'll examine some of the unique challenges faced by a project like Roslyn - huge backwards compatibility requirements, hard to meet performance scenarios, and more.                          </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Kevin Pilch-Bisson </SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/How-its-made-Behind-the-scenes-of-building-Microsoft-Roslyn-Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Brian Rasmussen</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Brian is a Senior SDET at Microsoft working on the next generation C# and Visual Basic language services in Roslyn. Before joining Microsoft Brian was a Microsoft MVP for C# for four years. </SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>1333035b-f2d9-4693-9f74-94dda8b21b53</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Kevin-PilchBisson-</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>How to Build Resilient &amp; Scalable PHP Applications on Amazon Web Services</Title>
		<Abstract>Amazon Web Services (AWS) provides a deceptively simple method of building PHP apps in the cloud.  However, AWS is fundamentally different from traditional hosting environments in a number of important ways.  Jamie and Mike from RightBrain Networks will be discussing best practices, common mistakes, and cost-saving strategies every PHP developer using AWS should know. Included will be lessons learned and architecture examples from real-life deployments.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Rosewood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jamie Begin</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>PHP</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/How-to-Build-Resilient--Scalable-PHP-Applications-on-Amazon-Web-Services</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Michael Gimbel</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Michael is the lead software engineer at RightBrain Networks. He recently comes from ePrize, where he spent five years helping build some of the most highly-trafficked promotional websites on the Internet for such clients as Coca-Cola, Microsoft, General Mills, MTV, and others. He holds a Computer Science degree from the University of Michigan College of Engineering and specializes in building highly-scalable, cloud-based applications.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>cac98b4b-0168-4c62-a32b-3fb52f31d826</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jamie-Begin</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>How to make the C# Compiler (or Team) Cry</Title>
		<Abstract>C# is a wonderfully powerful language, with each new release bringing new shiny toys for developers. Normally we would only use these features for honorable purposes, but... well, it's fun to abuse languages occasionally. I've rarely met a language feature I haven't found some way of twisting in weird and wonderful ways.

I will do my utmost to make sure that absolutely none of the code presented in this talk will be suitable for production use, but that all of it will be entertaining and possibly eye-watering. Let's face it, you didn't really come to CodeMash to learn, did you?

</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Advanced</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jon Skeet</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/How-to-make-the-C-Compiler-or-Team-Cry</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>4471f390-93f2-4978-aa85-e1e46642eeba</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jon-Skeet</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>How to Start a Company</Title>
		<Abstract>Got a great idea?  Setting up something on the side with a couple coworkers?  Great!  Now what?  Should you sign something about who has ownership?  What exactly is an LLC or an EIN?  Is the text message from your client okaying the project cost good enough?  What about that guy who dropped out early on?  This session explores the legal nuts and bolts of how to go into business - how to establish a business entity, what you agree on now to avoid litigation later, when to get a lawyer involved in dealing with a customer, and why you should never, ever agree with your friends that you are "partners".</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Benjamin Winkler</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Business</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/How-to-Start-a-Company</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>0c554e88-a2cc-4a9d-a3c6-8bf34fffdf0a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Benjamin-Winkler</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>How we Took Our Server-side Application to the Cloud and Liked What We Got</Title>
		<Abstract> Taking traditional Java server-side applications to the multi-tenant Cloud introduces lots of challenges. In this session, we will share our experience of creating a SaaS offering, which is currently being used successfully by the Java community. We will start by reviewing the challenges we faced during the SaaS conversion. Next, we will share our experience with the EC2 platform. We will discuss the importance of automation and how we use tools like Chef and Puppet for SaaS provisioning. Finally, we will describe how creating a SaaS version of our product shifted our way of thinking about software release. We will recommend what&#x2019;s required to successfully release both SaaS and downloadable versions of your product.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Rosewood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Frederic Simon</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Java</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/How-we-Took-Our-Serverside-Application-to-the-Cloud-and-Liked-What-We-Got</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>8433ba63-625f-4db5-ab50-f38f44f3ed2b</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Frederic-Simon</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>HTML 5 and the Great Mobile Debate</Title>
		<Abstract>A year ago, hybrid development frameworks like PhoneGap that leverage HTML5 were poised to radically alter mobile app development.  A year later, the potential has failed to live up to the promise: Faster/Easier/Cheaper doesn't always mean Better. Going Native often times still remains the best way to go. And Native doesn't have to mean Objective-C or Java -- there's a bevy of innovative mobile development frameworks gaining momentum that ultimately produce a legitimate native application that doesn't suffer from an underwhelming user experience associated with poorly built mobile web apps. What's more, in this stage of mobile's evolution, multi-platform doesn't always have to be a requirement. What is a primary requirement, however, is U/X and this is where HTML5 lacks Native parity. 

In this presentation, I'll address the Great Mobile Debate head-on -- you'll learn the current state of HTML 5 and understand what's good about it and what isn't. I'll show you where HTML 5 makes sense and how to leverage it correctly, and then I'll demonstrate an impressive list of mobile development frameworks that enable you to build awesome Native apps that consumers demand. And these frameworks don't demand mastery of Objective-C or Java -- like PhoneGap they abstract the raw platform, but unlike PhoneGap, they ultimately build an app capable of wowing an end user. 
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Andrew Glover</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/HTML-5-and-the-Great-Mobile-Debate</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>c438a177-0cc8-4ce2-9c4a-89305c8eac1a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Andrew-Glover</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>HTML5 Workshop (Wednesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>HTML5 is exciting, and it does have the potential to change the Web as we know it, but it also gets blown out of proportion. What&#x2019;s more, its true meaning can be elusive. It&#x2019;s a broad topic, so it&#x2019;s difficult to wrap your head around HTML5, much less know where to begin with this exciting new set of technologies. 
  
That's where our pre-compiler comes in. 
  
Over the course of a half-day, we (Brandon Satrom and Clark Sell) will tell you everything you need to know to get started with the next generation of open web technologies. We'll start with an overview of what HTML5 is, and why it matters, before moving quickly through major aspects of the core HTML5 specifications. Then, we'll discuss highlights of CSS3, major new JavaScript APIs and language features, before we end with a discussion on graceful degradation and adopting HTML5 without leaving older browsers behind.  Throughout the day, we'll mix in hands-on exercises and labs so that you can leave with a working understanding of these technologies, and how you can begin to apply them immediately. This session is platform agnostic, so all you need to attend get your hands dirty is a text editor (like TextMate, Vim, e, Visual Studio or WebMatrix) and your favorite, modern browser to learn how to make the web shine.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Brandon Satrom</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Web</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/HTML5-Workshop-Wednesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Clark Sell</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Forthcoming</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>a245399f-d41d-4598-9ecc-9646927d42e8</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Brandon-Satrom</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>I Am Designer and So Can You!</Title>
		<Abstract>For many developers, design does not come naturally. Lucky for you, you have ME! (Congrats on your recent acquisition of my friendship and knowledge.) Let me be the first to tell you design isn&#x2019;t as complicated as it may seem. It all boils down to three basic strategies that we&#x2019;ll discuss in this session.

First, we&#x2019;ll go over the fundamentals of grid structure. This will include how to set the content to maximize space allowance, and create an appropriate hierarchy to convey your content based on importance. Second, we&#x2019;ll take a brief trip down color-theory lane. Theory? Yes, there is theory behind all UI color choices and you&#x2019;ll learn what that means and why. Last, get ready, this is the big finale; we&#x2019;re going to talk type! Type is a huge part of design and is often neglected or simply thought of as the alphabet. Each typeface tells a story and you want to make sure you&#x2019;re picking one that&#x2019;s right for your message.

If all of this sounds over your head, fear not, I&#x2019;ll hold your hand and go slow. This session is for design beginners, people who have an interest in design, or just those of you who&#x2019;d like to be able to understand your own designers better.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Justine Arreche</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Design/UX</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/I-Am-Designer-and-So-Can-You</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>71a5399d-d221-465f-915f-1e407d8b40a8</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Justine-Arreche</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>I Didn't Know JavaScript Could Do That! The Missing Introduction to the World's Most Misunderstood Language</Title>
		<Abstract>JavaScript used to be a language that most ASP.NET developers shied away from, or only used it for some simple form validation. With the ascent of jQuery, developers are realizing that JavaScript is more than just a way to validate data or perform some simple functions. It's a powerful language that is quickly becoming the engine driving most web applications. But for most developers, their exposure is limited to using JavaScript through frameworks, such as jQuery, and they really haven't been exposed to the true power of JavaScript.

In this session, we'll learn about some features of JavaScript that you may not be familiar with. From the concepts of truthy and falsey, to extending your objects through prototypal inheritence (and properly exposing your object's functions), we'll take a tour through the JavaScript language that will make you say "I Didn't Know JavaScript Could Do That!". </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>David Hoerster</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/I-Didnt-Know-JavaScript-Could-Do-That-The-Missing-Introduction-to-the-Worlds-Most-Misunderstood-Language</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>7381843e-f9c4-465f-a76b-5dc8db486538</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/David-Hoerster</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Intermediate Software Craftsmanship (Wednesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Join your peers and fellow craftsmen in a variety of coding kata and exercises designed to improve your skills as software developers. Led by organizers of the Hudson Software Craftsmanship group, this interactive session will help you sharpen your tools and learn from others. Experienced developers from all backgrounds are welcome, as are beginners (who might consider attending the morning's Beginning Software Craftsmanship session, though it's not required). Attendees should already be comfortable with a programming language of their choice and if possible should bring along a laptop computer with their development tools installed, including a unit testing tool.  This session will focus on group design, refactoring, and application of design patterns to improve the design of existing software.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Steve Smith</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Craftsmanship</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Intermediate-Software-Craftsmanship-Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Brendan Enrick</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Brendan Enrick works for Telerik as a Lead Developer in their Services Division. Brendan is one of the founders and organizers of the Hudson Software Craftsmanship group, which meets monthly in Hudson, Ohio, between Akron and Cleveland. Brendan keeps a software development blog focusing on software craftsmanship, agile, and other development topics. His blog can be found at http://Brendan.Enrick.com/ and his twitter alias is @Brendoneus.
</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>473ce128-a5bc-4b83-8940-fb0f65c3e60f</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Steve-Smith</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Intermediate Xbox 360 Development with the XNA Framework</Title>
		<Abstract>The methods for producing quality games that perform in real time are much different than the methods used to produce quality productivity software. Sure, you've slapped some sprites on the screen, but do you have the tools to turn those sprites into a full experience. This session will present attendees with the nuances of proper game design by introducing topics such as the game components, sprite animation, background music, sound effects, and threading.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Indigo Bay</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Chris Gardner</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Game Development</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Intermediate-Xbox-360-Development-with-the-XNA-Framework</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>84a15fea-81c5-4462-930d-fc107f7041f5</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Chris-Gardner</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Into the Mind of a Hacker. (Wednesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>In this session Bill and Rob dig deep into the world of exploits and malware with a specific emphasis on explaining the process by which these tools are created and reverse engineered. This is a step well beyond running "exploit" from within msfconsole and attendees should expect to see a fair bit of assembly and register-level debugging.
 
The purpose of this session is not to build an army of cyber miscreants but rather to help you understand how attackers look at your software, and the types of things they are looking to exploit. You will leave this session with a better idea of how you can protect your applications from being an unknown carrier of the next bit of malware to sweep the 'Net.
 
This session starts with a demonstration of crafting an exploit (identifying a weakness, testing for specific vulnerabilities, execution and "weaponization").  We then dig into the internals of Windows and arm you with the tools and understanding to begin working through an exploited machine and understanding what the malware has been doing on the infected system.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Ironwood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Rob Gillen</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Security</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Into-the-Mind-of-a-Hacker-Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Bill Sempf</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Bill Sempf is a software architect.  His breadth of experience includes business and technical analysis, software design, development, testing, server management and maintenance, and security.  In his 17 years of professional experience he has participated in the creation of well over 200 applications for large and small companies, managed the software infrastructure of two Internet service providers, coded complex software happily in every environment imaginable, and made mainframes talk to cell phones. 
 
He is the author of C# 2010 All in One for Dummies; a coauthor of Effective Visual Studio.NET and many other books, a frequent contributor to industry magazines; and has recently been an invited speaker for the ACM and IEEE, CodeMash, DerbyCon, BSides, DevEssentials, the International XML Web Services Expo and the Association of Information Technology Professionals. Bill also serves on the board of the Columbus branch of the Open Web Application Security Project, and is the Administrative Director of Locksport International.
</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>975874cc-c5fd-4ae3-b034-d86c61c4f6c2</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Rob-Gillen</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Intro to GIS and Mapping on the Internet Using Free and Open Source Tools</Title>
		<Abstract>Let's dive into the depths of GIS and mapping on the Internet. OpenLayers, Google Maps javascript API, PostGIS, GeoServer, and others. There is an opportunity now with Javascript APIs and amazing open source GIS servers/tools to express your creativity by building beautiful maps, and visualize information like never before. We will cover the basics of building a browser based mapping application, and go behind the scenes with the very capable PostGIS (built on PostgreSQL), and show you how these tools all fit together to build a complete solution.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Steve Horn</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Intro-to-GIS-and-Mapping-on-the-Internet-Using-Free-and-Open-Source-Tools</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>02099cde-4e5b-4935-b4cf-09d46a5bad1d</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Steve-Horn</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Introducing Android</Title>
		<Abstract>If you are new to Android this session is for you. We will cover Android basics and then walk through building an application to display data from a web service. We will parse the JSON returned and display it. We will also cover async tasks and how to cascade async operations.

Additionally we will cover how to store and retrieve settings in your application. This session will cover a variety of aspects that come in play when designing an android enterprise application.  We will also discuss fragments.

If you would like to follow along, bring a laptop with android sdk loaded. </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Parag Joshi</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Introducing-Android</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>e33c6cda-2354-45cc-ba3c-59bbaf087a77</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Parag-Joshi</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Introducing PhoneGap</Title>
		<Abstract>Target multiple mobile platforms with the same code using PhoneGap. Adam will create a mobile application for both iPhone and Android by the end of the demonstration. In this introduction to PhoneGap, learn to leverage your current skill set: integrate HTML, JavaScript, and jQuery with simple OData integration.  Adam will also discuss the advantages and disadvantages of using a cross-platform environment for building mobile applications.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Indigo Bay</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Adam Ryder</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Introducing-PhoneGap</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>b94fe9c5-0bd6-4ca7-8d8b-9d837b8929d0</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Adam-Ryder</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>iOS 6 - The Perfect Time to Start Developing for iPhone and iPad</Title>
		<Abstract>You've been meaning to write an app for the App Store for years. It turns out that all of your delays have really paid off. This is the perfect time to get started writing apps for iPhone and iPad. The tools, the language, and the platform has matured.

In this session we'll take a brief look at the four cornerstones of developing for the iOS platform. You'll take a quick look at Xcode, the IDE for creating your apps, and Objective-C, the language for iOS development. We'll then take a brief tour of View Controllers, the anchors of any Cocoa Touch application, and storyboards. </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Dan Steinberg</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/iOS-6--The-Perfect-Time-to-Start-Developing-for-iPhone-and-iPad</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>33dd5527-faa3-46d4-b11a-f76d526159e2</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Dan-Steinberg</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>iOS 6 Quick Start (Wednesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>You'll learn what it takes to write an iPhone or iPad app in the few hours between breakfast and lunch.

The first half of this hands-on session will get you started creating projects in Xcode and working with the basics of Objective-C. After the break we'll play with the patterns of iOS development for getting the most out of View Controllers and storyboards. Our goal with this session is to give you a sense of what iOS development is all about. Once you're done you can go to the books, the tutorials, and the Apple docs to build the apps you want.

If you want to code along with us, you'll need to bring a Mac running at least OS X 10.7 Lion but preferably OS X 10.8 Mountain Lion. Download and install the latest version of Xcode from the Mac App Store. Also, you'll be happier if you download the documentation from Xcode's preferences pane.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Aloeswood/Lepoardwood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Daniel Steinberg</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>iOS</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/iOS-6-Quick-Start-Wednesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>873a503e-b25c-469a-9501-7c0dea458a58</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Daniel-Steinberg</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Jack (or Java) and the Beanstalk   </Title>
		<Abstract>Amazon is providing the ability to leverage their resources as a full scale PaaS in elastic beanstalk. We'll discuss how elastic beanstalk works, show what it takes to setup a simple Java webapp and launch it up in Amazon. Talk about other services that can be easily leveraged within AWS to help support application deployments of this type. Also cover other platforms and deployment methods Amazon supports with Beanstalk. </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Travis Smith</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Java</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Jack-or-Java-and-the-Beanstalk---</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>0492506d-54da-458a-b802-032bd51a9cd4</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Travis-Smith</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Java in the (Amazon) Clouds  (Wednesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Wonder what all the Cloud Computing hype is about? Want to know how to deploy a standard Java web application to the cloud and get limitless scalability? Well, this hands on tutorial will answer all your questions and provide confidence by walking you through the process of deploying a sophisticated Java web application to the Amazon Web Service (AWS) Cloud. During this tutorial you will provision clustered servers (EC2), relational database (EC2 and EBS), load balancer (Elastic Load Balancing),  content delivery (Cloud Front) and how to monitor your whole infrastructure. Other Amazon Web Services will be demonstrated and discussed as appropriate.

Note: An Amazon Web Services Account is a nice to have and will incur a minimal cost during the tutorial but is not a requirement. Access to AWS will be provided to you if you don&#x2019;t already have access.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Christopher Judd</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Cloud</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Java-in-the-Amazon-Clouds--Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Nathan Zender</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Nathan Zender is a Columbus-based independent consultant and code slinger who loves 
all things technology. Nathan's areas of expertise include web development with Groovy &amp; Grails, Java, 
Javascript (jQuery is my second love), TDD and agile development. When not developing he spends his time
with his wife (hint : this is my first love) and 2 dogs. 
</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>20997d8c-f18e-44c2-a26e-98b9e3610096</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Christopher-Judd</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>JVM Bytecode for Dummies</Title>
		<Abstract>You've written applications for the JVM, using various frameworks and maybe even various languages. You understand how to rig up the CLASSPATH, get .class files to load, compile source, and set up an IDE. But you've always wanted a better understanding of the plumbing underneath. How does JVM bytecode work? How does the JVM itself work? This tallk will walk you through JVM and JVM bytecode basics, with lots of examples how to subvert the JVM to your whims.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Charles Oliver Nutter</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Java</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/JVM-Bytecode-for-Dummies</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>9095e30f-6f5e-440e-9e73-939ec3deeae2</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Charles-Oliver-Nutter</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>JVM JIT for Dummies</Title>
		<Abstract>You think you know all there is about building apps for the JVM. You've used all the cool tools. You've written your own persistence library or web frameworks. Maybe you've even implemented a JVM language. But do you really know what happens to your code after you hand it off to the JVM? This talk will explore the guts of the OpenJDK VM, Hotspot. We'll take a few simple examples from bytecode through optimization and compilation all the way down to assembly code, and learn how you can ensure your code runs as fast as possible.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Charles Oliver Nutter</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Java</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/JVM-JIT-for-Dummies</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>b39838bc-afeb-40f9-a41d-dc40d4b7b414</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Charles-Oliver-Nutter</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Keynote</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-10T13:15:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T14:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Neal Ford</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Keynote</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>7f68a8bb-f6f2-46ed-94aa-f2ecf2d7f216</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Neal-Ford</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>KidzMash: Internet Safety</Title>
		<Abstract>Internet safety</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T15:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</End>
		<Room>Acacia</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Richard Campbell</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/KidzMash-Internet-Safety</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>8707b537-9ac0-4012-b398-7d3ff1e5c776</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Richard-Campbell</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>KidzMash: Kidz in Control</Title>
		<Abstract>Kidz in even MORE control</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T21:00:00Z</End>
		<Room>Acacia</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Aydin Akcasu</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/KidzMash-Kidz-in-Control</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>c3b94c8b-be35-498b-a869-f3ca829b8946</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Aydin-Akcasu</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>KidzMash: Negotiation &amp; Design Strategies</Title>
		<Abstract>Negotiation and design strategies</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Acacia</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Carol Smith</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/KidzMash-Negotiation--Design-Strategies</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>327044c9-cbbe-42d5-80a7-b5159c7c8d64</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Carol-Smith</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>KidzMash: Programming Kinect</Title>
		<Abstract>Programming Kinect with gestures</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Acacia</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Carl Franklin</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/KidzMash-Programming-Kinect</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>c7e8cf98-cdfe-4914-ab8a-28f98bfe978d</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Carl-Franklin</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>KidzMash: R/C Helicopters</Title>
		<Abstract>Programming remote control helicopters</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T19:00:00Z</End>
		<Room>Acacia</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Matt Vanvleet</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/KidzMash-RC-Helicopters</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>b81ff933-9c9f-4a6c-a914-78e5c9a87073</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Matt-Vanvleet</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>KidzMash: Why I Write Software</Title>
		<Abstract>Looking at programming as a career choice</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Acacia</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jeff Blankenburg</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/KidzMash-Why-I-Write-Software</URI>
		<EventType>KidzMash</EventType>
		<Id>9df45a30-ecfe-4fa7-8be8-d883eb18a88b</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jeff-Blankenburg</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Lean and Mean Domain Objects in Active Record (Tuesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Rails apps that have been extensively enhanced and maintained over the last few years are starting to fall apart under their own weight. Developers have struggled trying to find the most appropriate area to place logic within the system. Initially the ease of writing views in ERB led many developers to stow code at the front of the application. Then we began finding the views to difficult to maintain so we moved the logic into controllers or helpers. Eventually this also became difficult to maintain so we developed "best practices" like skinny controllers and fat models. Active Record domain models naturally become the dumping ground of logic within the system but sooner or later this leads to brittle, unmaintainable, bug filled systems.
Coupling persistence, validation, advanced querying, and business logic all into the same class inevitably leads to extremely fat models with any system of significance. Skinny controllers are definitely worth striving for, but shoveling all of the business logic into a class that is already overburdened with with three other concerns is a recipe for disaster. When you find yourself using factories, fixtures, or mocks to construct 8 different class dependencies, it's time to admit that fat models are not a solution worth aspiring to.
This talk will cover some different approaches for segregating the multiple concerns of fat Active Record models into loosely coupled, cohesive classes with single responsibilities. We'll dive into the both the process for refactoring these plump classes along with some better patterns of use for common AR bloat.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Todd Kaufman</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Ruby</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Lean-and-Mean-Domain-Objects-in-Active-Record-Tuesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Jason Karns</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Jason Karns is a bit of a code nomad, having called PHP, .NET, Java and now Ruby his home. A common thread across all platforms is his passion for well-crafted software and enjoyment in web application development. Jason is still searching for a way to combine programming and golf into the epitome of activities. In his free time, Jason ships software through Test Double from Columbus, Ohio.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>16608dd2-d8e3-4e06-a562-2355640a43eb</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Todd-Kaufman</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Lessons from Two Years of Backbone.js</Title>
		<Abstract>Backbone.js has exploded in popularity in the past couple years.  As one of the earlier shops to embrace it, we've learned a lot about how to use it more effectively over time.  We'll start with introducing backbone.js to catch everybody up that hasn't used it, but spend most of this session digging in a little deeper to cover topics like composite views, model relationships, error response handling, memory management, just to name a few. Expect to get a lot of out of this talk if you're new to backbone or even if you've been using it for awhile.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Chris Nelson</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Lessons-from-Two-Years-of-Backbonejs</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>cae26cf2-72b2-4fa9-8c5d-d6cb15a245c1</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Chris-Nelson</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Lunch - Friday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-11T17:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T18:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Lunch--Friday</URI>
		<EventType>Meal</EventType>
		<Id>909fa04b-be35-4609-bef1-1309bd1b8f99</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Lunch - Thursday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-10T17:15:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T18:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Lunch--Thursday</URI>
		<EventType>Meal</EventType>
		<Id>d87f01e8-8d08-4c35-839d-d5f63d2ed4d9</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Lunch - Tuesday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-08T17:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T18:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Lunch--Tuesday</URI>
		<EventType>Meal</EventType>
		<Id>237a1637-839d-4a31-8df3-22985be4d14d</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Lunch - Wednesday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Dining Room</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Lunch--Wednesday</URI>
		<EventType>Meal</EventType>
		<Id>76b8d286-4ee2-46e9-9f4a-6d3105d8c06f</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Machine Learning - Predicting the Future</Title>
		<Abstract>Often folks focus on OLAP and Relational Reporting as the primary focus of BI and as such miss out on the tremendous computational gems provided by standard machine learning algorithms. Additionally, classification (or predictive inference) is only half of what machine learning has to offer. Unsupervised learning, as a discipline, incorporates many non-predictive principles that allow for the condensing of large amounts of data in a structured and predictable way. The purpose of this session is to demystify the central ideas behind pattern recognition and machine learning by demonstrating the fundamental concepts behind classification. Most developers shy away from such algorithms simply because of their perceived difficulty while missing the inherent simplicity of these approaches. This session will demonstrate how a computer can learn from labeled examples in order to predict appropriate labels for future examples.

The session will highlight Decision Trees, the Perceptron Algorithm, and introduce attendees to non-linear classifiers through the standard Kernel Trick. This friendly introduction will allow attendees to begin using these standard algorithms to create predictive software without the hassle of having to write difficult code.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Seth Juarez</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Machine-Learning--Predicting-the-Future</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>fbe66ad9-c1ff-4ab7-be74-7b3da45c81c7</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Seth-Juarez</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Machine Learning - Understanding the Past</Title>
		<Abstract>Often folks focus on OLAP and Relational Reporting as the primary focus of BI and as such miss out on the tremendous computational gems provided by standard machine learning algorithms. Additionally, classification (or predictive inference) is only half of what machine learning has to offer. Unsupervised learning, as a discipline, incorporates many non-predictive principles that allow for the condensing of large amounts of data in a structured and predictable way. The purpose of this session is to demystify the central ideas behind pattern recognition and machine learning by demonstrating the fundamental concepts behind classification. Most developers shy away from such algorithms simply because of their perceived difficulty while missing the inherent simplicity of these approaches. This session will demonstrate how a computer can learn from unlabeled examples in order to learn the structure of data and its implications for the future. This session will highlight the popular KMeans Algorithm, Hierarchical Clustering, as well as the standard dimensionality reducing technique called Principal Component Analysis. This friendly introduction will allow attendees to begin using these standard algorithms to create inductive software without the hassle of having to write difficult code.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Seth Juarez</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Machine-Learning--Understanding-the-Past</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>1c243396-acc9-4b71-bdaf-19dff1f7c91f</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Seth-Juarez</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Making Test Automation with Web Applications Work (Wednesday Half Day, AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>In a perfect world we would have automated test coverage for every significant part of our web applications that consistently provides quick and useful regression feedback.  In the real world automated testing efforts frequently fail because the tests are too time-consuming to author, too brittle when the underlying application changes, too flaky with asynchronous timing, or just flat out too slow.  After way too much teeth gnashing and a lot of struggling, I think my team has hit on a workable formula for successful test automation.  I&#x2019;ll share our lessons learned about which tests are worth writing and which aren&#x2019;t, balancing cheaper whitebox tests versus more comprehensive blackbox testing, and how to express the test scenarios to promote readability and minimize coupling.  I&#x2019;ll show you some relatively simple strategies for dealing with asynchronous screen behavior.  I&#x2019;ll demonstrate the approach we use to make setting up test data as declarative as possible while trying to decouple the test scenarios from being coupled to the application internals.  Lastly, I&#x2019;ll talk about the application architecture choices you can make to reduce the effort to reward ration of your automated testing effort. 
My previous team used StoryTeller, WebDriver, Jasmine, and TeamCity to create and execute our automated tests, but I believe that these techniques are applicable to other tools like Cucumber, SpecFlow,m or WatiN/Watir as well.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jeremy Miller</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Making-Test-Automation-with-Web-Applications-Work-Wednesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Josh Arnold</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Joshua is a husband, father, passionate software craftsman, and aspiring man of God. He&#x2019;s one of the principal developers of the Fubu family of frameworks and spontaneous blogger at LosTechies. He slings code for a living and dreams of ways to take over the world. 
 
He has run the ranks of tester, developer, manager, and back. He helps lead teams in the adoption of better practices, zero-friction tooling, and advanced automated testing. He is currently a Team Lead with Extend Health.
</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>6b08c4db-a3e6-4ee0-94a3-2b3fda568b09</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jeremy-Miller</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Managing Modular Software for your NuGet, C++ and Java Development</Title>
		<Abstract>Binary repository is one of the cornerstones of building modular software. In this session we will demonstrate how it can be used to support modular development in Java, C++ and the .NET platform (using NuGet).
Next, we will show how to take the binary repository one step forward to support Continuous Deployment and Release Management by using build integration features which allow full traceability and automation of staging and release procedures. </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Frederic Simon</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Continuous Deployment</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Managing-Modular-Software-for-your-NuGet-C-and-Java-Development</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>bcc72e97-582c-4f3d-8612-c433d2aba4f1</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Frederic-Simon</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Mastering ActiveRecord Scopes and Active Relationship</Title>
		<Abstract>Most Rails developers only tap the surface of what ActiveRecord provides and never utilize the power of ActiveRelationship (ARel). ActiveRecord allows you to mix and match scopes in addition to merge scopes from related models to prevent duplication and provide great flexibility in composing your data. Additionally, you can leverage ActiveRelationship to write complex joins, selects, aggregations and even unions which can also be merged as scopes to cleanly build queries. This talk will teach you how you can use ActiveRecord and ActiveRelationship together in order to build flexible and powerful sql queries without actually ever writing a line of raw sql.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Dan Shultz</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Ruby</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Mastering-ActiveRecord-Scopes-and-Active-Relationship</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>fed06d33-7554-4aa8-86a6-2618b3e86871</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Dan-Shultz</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Mixer</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-08T23:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T01:00:00Z</End>
		<Room>TBD</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Mixer</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>a1192b59-1a36-4e8e-b7cb-164730a61110</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Netflix's OSS Cloud</Title>
		<Abstract>This talk presents a general overview of the Netflix cloud architecture built upon theAmazon Web Services (AWS) foundation. It covers how we use existing AWS features to improve the manageability of our cloud objects, and how we add a few abstractions to tie the AWS objects neatly together.

It also covers some of the Netflix OSS tools (and a few non-OSS), and how they fit into this picture to help run the show. Among those covered will be:

   * Asgard - A web interface for application deployments and cloud management in AWS.
   * Archaius - A library and API for live configuration management.
   * Eureka - A service registry for resilient mid-tier load balancing and failover.
   * SimianArmy - Tools for keeping your cloud operating in top form. Chaos Monkey is a resiliency tool that helps applications tolerate random instance failures.
   * Servo - The Netflix Application Monitoring Library
   * Epic / Atlas (not yet OSS): complete central monitoring system and dashboard
   * Chronos (not yet OSS): The central log of fine-grained events detailing everything that happens in AWS
   * CAG (not yet OSS): The central alerting gateway for directing emails and pages.
   * Edda - A central log of AWS object life cycles for historic reference.
   * Bakeri - The baker of AMIs.
   * Odin - A client-side framework for driving automation of the above.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Carl Quinn</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Java</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Netflixs-OSS-Cloud</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>f0388b98-112c-4ce8-8a24-22950c9f541d</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Carl-Quinn</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>NFC Application Development on Android 4.x</Title>
		<Abstract>Near Fields Communication (NFC) is popular in commercial applications but now-a-days is gaining attraction at consumer level through smart phone devices. NFC has a strong potential in various industries like Finance, eCommerce, Entertainment, Logistics, Security etc. and new Android devices are getting introduced with NFC technology built in and ready to use.

In this session, Hari Bawa will cover getting started developing NFC application using Android 4.x API along with demo.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Harimohan Bawa</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/NFC-Application-Development-on-Android-4x</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>e137d835-ca10-457a-b9fb-4b92028d850b</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Harimohan-Bawa</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Not Everything is an Object: Functional Superiority with Clojure</Title>
		<Abstract>We all know the saying that when your only tool is a hammer then every problem looks like Justin Bieber's face. If your only tool is an OO language then you start to force every solution domain into fitting the standard OO solution domain. This is flawed thinking and leads to broken or brittle software. In this session I'll show you that not every problem is well suited to an OO solution and what other solutions are available to you, with examples in Clojure.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Gary Short</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Clojure</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Not-Everything-is-an-Object-Functional-Superiority-with-Clojure</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>f9258583-37de-43db-bf58-0a57d582deb8</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Gary-Short</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>NServiceBus Crash Course (Tuesday All Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>Interested in learning how to build reliable systems? Curious to see what NServiceBus brings over technologies like WCF? Or just want to learn about reliable messaging?

Bring your laptop, and we'll examine through hands-on coding how NServiceBus builds reliability in. We'll tour the major messaging patterns - One-way sending, request/reply, pub/sub, sagas and more. We'll also see what NServiceBus adds on top of messaging frameworks like Azure Queues and MSMQ. Finally, I'll share some of my experiences bringing unreliable systems under control with durable messaging.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jimmy Bogard</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/NServiceBus-Crash-Course-Tuesday-All-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>a926bcd6-e2ab-4816-acf3-dc60b057191f</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jimmy-Bogard</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>NSPredicates for Fun and Profit</Title>
		<Abstract>NSPredicates aren&#x2019;t just for Core Data. NSPredicates are part of the
Foundation classes and can be used with collections in ways that make
your code more testable and easier to maintain. They are, however not
well documented and notoriously difficult to create. Sure, once
created they are easy to use and let you do things that are very
difficult without them. In this intermediate session we will cover
what NSPredicates are, where they can be used, how to debug them, and
how to replace difficult to maintain iterative code with elegant
predicates. You should have a good understanding of Objective C and
the collections. While we will cover some of Core Data, this is not a
Core Data session.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Joshua Smith</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/NSPredicates-for-Fun-and-Profit</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>14ece4a9-d823-44c5-8e81-58d6699674b1</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Joshua-Smith</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Objective-C Is Not Java</Title>
		<Abstract>Look past the square braces and the damned header files and Objective-C -- the essential language of iOS development -- really isn't that different from other object-oriented languages. Classes, single-inheritance, polymorphism, implementation hiding... check, check, check, and check. So it's really not that difficult for old Java / Python / Ruby / C++ dogs to learn new tricks once they install Xcode, right?
To be a competent Obj-C programmer, not that hard.
To be a great Obj-C programmer... now that's another story.
In this session, we will look at traits that are unique to Objective-C, the tricks that bring out the expressiveness and power of the language. We'll also look at how to write idiomatic code that will be easily understood and maintained by other Objective-C developers. We'll look at how Automatic Reference Counting resembles but is really nothing like Garbage Collection, how properties put plain old instance variables to shame, how we loosely couple classes with delegates and notification, how blocks help us un-block our code by simplifying asynchronicity, and more.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Chris Adamson</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/ObjectiveC-Is-Not-Java</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>af779a63-8c76-4ec1-8c1f-016f5e0b868f</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Chris-Adamson</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Panel Discussion</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-10T00:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T01:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>TBD</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>TBD</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Panel-Discussion</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>f72a868f-3811-46c2-ac27-7418fa793250</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/TBD</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Pecha Kucha</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-11T00:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T02:00:00Z</End>
		<Room>TBD</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Pecha-Kucha</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>63998ff3-da62-4a39-b939-b5d585e88a2e</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Performance, Productivity. Pick Two with Dart.</Title>
		<Abstract>Be productive building high-performance web apps! Learn how to use Dart to build structured apps for the entire modern web, and scale from small scripts to large apps. Bonus: see how you can build with Web Components today with Dart.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Seth Ladd</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Performance-Productivity-Pick-Two-with-Dart</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>04e95cb0-7633-4ec3-b232-12b298d87be7</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Seth-Ladd</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Practicing Continuous Delivery</Title>
		<Abstract>This session will teach you best practices and patterns for doing Continuous Delivery / Continuous Deployment in Cloud environments. You will learn how to handle schema migrations, maintain dev/prod parity, manage configuration and scaling.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Aloeswood/Leopardswood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>James Ward</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Continuous Deployment</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Practicing-Continuous-Delivery</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>367d6cbe-1ecd-4142-918f-4bb759e49e83</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/James-Ward</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Processing Big Data with MongoDB</Title>
		<Abstract>An introduction to MongoDB&#x2019;s tools to technologies to efficiently process large quantities of data. Topics include:

Map-Reduce Useful for batch processing of data and aggregation operations. It is similar in spirit to Hadoop with all input coming from a collection and output going to a collection. Map and reduce functions are written in JavaScript and execute on the server.

The Aggregation Framework is an alternate to Map-Reduce while providing a powerful means to calculate aggregate values. The aggregation framework can be used to perform SQL-like group-bys, distincts and self-joins. The aggregation framework also provides projection facilities which reshape data, add computed fields, create virtual sub-objects, and to extract sub-fields to results.

Hadoop Integration is a series of plugins for the Hadoop platform to allow connectivity to MongoDB The Hadoop connector allows both reading MongoDB data into Hadoop (for use in MapReduce jobs as well as other components of the Hadoop ecosystem), as well as writing the results of Hadoop jobs out to MongoDB.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Rosewood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Bryan Reinero</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Processing-Big-Data-with-MongoDB</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>59b506cc-0909-4b40-95f2-33555ee4feb2</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Bryan-Reinero</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Puppet for Developers</Title>
		<Abstract>Puppet is a configuration management tool that allows easy and automated provisioning of servers by describing the packages, configuration, and system services. Along with continuous integration tools like Jenkins, it is a means to accomplishing continuous delivery, automating the operations side, and enabling testing of systems configuration. While systems provisioning is traditionally for system administrators, Puppet can empower developers. When combining Vagrant with Puppet, developers can easily spin up virtual machines with the same configuration as production servers to do development or testing, and tear them down afterwards.

You will see how to install and manage Puppet nodes with installed web and database servers, config files, and all the supporting services. Learn how Puppet can provision Vagrant and VirtualBox for application and infrastructure testing. You'll also learn how to write your own custom Facts as well as how to test your Puppet manifests with RSpec.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon E</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Eric Hankinson</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other Languages</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Puppet-for-Developers</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>bd35d2d5-2896-4406-a5e1-f0eeb05041d6</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Eric-Hankinson</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Put Some Parentheses in your Browser: an introduction to ClojureScript</Title>
		<Abstract>ClojureScript is a new dialect of Clojure that compiles to JavaScript. We will discuss why you should consider using it over existing JavaScript languages like CoffeeScript, and cover build tools, web development libraries, how to use existing JavaScript libraries, and sharing code with the JVM.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Advanced</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Gary Fredericks</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Clojure</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Put-Some-Parentheses-in-your-Browser-an-introduction-to-ClojureScript</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>4adad46f-2634-448d-99dd-63afdd66ce40</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Gary-Fredericks</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Putting the D&amp;D in TDD (Wednesday All Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>Are you tired of TDD workshops that make you do boring things like calculate bowling scores and prime factors or demonstrate how to win at the game of life? If so, this is the session for you! In this TDD workshop we will be building the domain model for EverCraft -- a new MMORPG from Blizzards of the Coast.  We have lots of story cards prepared covering features from combat to magic, classes to spells, and races to items. Plus, we'll be defining some of these cards during the session in case you want that +9 knife of ogre slaying or enjoy casting magic missile at the darkness. 

This workshop is language agnotisic and for all levels of developers. The focus is on TDD and emergent design but pair programming will be covered as well. The only requirement is that you bring a laptop and that you be able to test-drive you code with your language of choice.  When you are done you will emerge a better programmer for the experience but there is small chance you will have a craving for Cheetos and Mountain Dew.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Guy Royse</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Putting-the-DD-in-TDD-Wednesday-All-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>George Walters II </SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>During the daylight hours, George works as an application developer for Nationwide Insurance. With more than 10 years experience in application development, he has become an advocate for building clean, concise code without sacrificing the user experience. He builds applications in an agile environment using a variety of technologies including Java, Objective-C, JavaScript and Ruby. He is also a strong promoter for using Adaptive and Responsive Design in all aspects of web development and pushes the need for developers to become stronger and more affluent in the Web UI stack of technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript). 

After dark, well, that's a different story...</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>bf4bff71-e825-428f-aace-d6c215bfc9c5</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Guy-Royse</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Putting your Backbone Apps on strings : Backbone Marionette and its Lessons about Backbone</Title>
		<Abstract>Backbone is one of the top MVC frameworks for JavaScript.  Backbone Marionette is an open source project that takes backbone makes it fast and easy.  I will take popular backbone patterns and show how quickly and efficiently they can be done with marionette.  From collection views to event handling, this talk will show you how to create better JavaScript front ends than you have made before.  The talk will explain how Marionette is coded and operates, so that even if you don&#x2019;t use it you can take back the techniques to your JavaScript code.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Mark Greenway</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Putting-your-Backbone-Apps-on-strings--Backbone-Marionette-and-its-Lessons-about-Backbone</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>6df5ff4b-9db7-42ba-a7be-fbf69ae2fb6c</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Mark-Greenway</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Quantum Entanglement for your Web Apps using SignalR and Knockout </Title>
		<Abstract>In physics, two particles can act together in order to behave as one system so that a change made to one particle instantly affects the other - even if they are separated by great distances. This is known as Quantum Entanglement, which Albert Einstein called "spooky action at a distance." The closest analogy to this for web development would be to observe a web page instantly update in response to a user entering data in a different web browser. Believe it or not, this is not only possible today, but relatively easy by using two open source libraries together: SignalR and Knockout. SignalR is an asynchronous signaling library for .NET that helps to build real-time, multi-user systems. Knockout is a JavaScript library that brings MVVM pattern to the web page, providing observable data, templates, and automatic data binding. This session will demonstrate how to use this new paradigm to build highly interactive web applications.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Aloeswood/Leopardswood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jason Follas</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Quantum-Entanglement-for-your-Web-Apps-using-SignalR-and-Knockout-</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>89cae6fa-a6e0-4186-9e9d-469d1ac917ef</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jason-Follas</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Rails for the .NET Developer</Title>
		<Abstract>"You live a new life for every new language you speak. If you know only one language, you live only once." -- Czech proverb
It's good to learn new languages and environments. Different languages solve the same problems in different ways. By learning several different approaches, you can help broaden your thinking and identify the right tool for the right job.
As someone who has spent the last few years using both environments on a daily basis, we will compare and contrast web development in the Microsoft .NET world vs. web development using the Ruby on Rails stack. We will compare the languages, the tooling, the communities, and the frameworks. This session will help the .NET developer get started down the Rails rabbit hole.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jamie Wright</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Ruby</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Rails-for-the-NET-Developer</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>78d49d21-9c1a-4c14-81fb-9e57a4014d4b</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jamie-Wright</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Rapid and Scalable Development with MongoDB, PyMongo, and Ming</Title>
		<Abstract>This intermediate-level talk will teach you techniques using the popular NoSQL database MongoDB and the Python library Ming to write maintainable, high-performance, and scalable applications. We will cover everything you need to become an effective Ming/MongoDB developer from basic PyMongo queries to high-level object-document mapping setups in Ming.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Rick Copeland</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Python</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Rapid-and-Scalable-Development-with-MongoDB-PyMongo-and-Ming</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>d6f4b83b-bfbb-4caf-80bd-31ca0eeeac2e</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Rick-Copeland</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Raspberry Pi Deep Dive</Title>
		<Abstract>The Raspberry Pi is a credit card sized computer developed by some Cambridge boffins. In this session I'll walk you through everything you need to do get up and running with it and then show you how to turn it into an Internet radio using Mono C# and VistaDB.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon G</Room>
		<Difficulty>Advanced</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Gary Short</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Hardware</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Raspberry-Pi-Deep-Dive</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>ef3b6e1c-56fd-4bc9-a1e7-2874ddc41a5f</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Gary-Short</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Reach the Mobile Masses with ASP.NET MVC 4 and jQuery Mobile</Title>
		<Abstract>Creating web applications that will target multiple devices and platforms has become the web developers Holy Grail. Simple HTML pages render without issue no matter what browser or device they are viewed on but who codes simple HTML pages? What happens when you have a business need to hit all mobile platforms?
You don't have to write hundreds of lines of code to make this happen! 
	
In this talk Keith will demonstrate how using the latest version of ASP.NET MVC, MVC4, and jQuery Mobile allows you to develop web applications that target iPhone, iPad, Android, Windows Phone 7, and even Blackberry without having to code and style each platform separately.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Rosewood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Keith Burnell</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Reach-the-Mobile-Masses-with-ASPNET-MVC-4-and-jQuery-Mobile</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>93afd10b-fd24-480f-a1d3-c06d7436ba54</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Keith-Burnell</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Realizing Agility with Scrum and Visual Studio 2012 (Tuesday All Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>This full-day pre-compiler introduces the Scrum framework and the supporting tools found in Visual Studio. Attendees will get a crash course in Scrum and if you are already experienced in Scrum, never fear! We&#x2019;ll provide value in the form of refinements and effective practices you can take back to your teams. 

After laying down a solid Scrum framework foundation, we&#x2019;ll explore features in Visual Studio 2012 and Team Foundation Server 2012 that specifically target increasing productivity for Scrum Teams. Features and techniques to enable collaboration, increase quality, and increase your Definition of Done will all be visited.

This workshop is a healthy mix of both the people side of Agile and the engineering practices that enable value-focused interactive/incremental development.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Alexei Govorine</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Process</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Realizing-Agility-with-Scrum-and-Visual-Studio-2012-Tuesday-All-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>David Starr</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>David Starr is a Senior Program Manager in the ALM Tools team at Microsoft where he focuses on Visual Studio Ultimate and tools that enable agile software development.
David served as Chief Craftsman for Scrum.org and was a Microsoft MVP in Visual Studio ALM for the five years prior to joining Microsoft. He focuses on agile software development, the Visual Studio ALM platform, and patterns and practices in .NET.  He enjoys helping software development teams improve and expressing human intent to computers.  Blog: elegantcode.com, Twitter: @elegantcoder
</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>d07109b7-3c59-4c71-a01a-af8f68220bad</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Alexei-Govorine</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Real-world JavaScript Testing (Wednesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Each year, more applications are being written for the browser entirely in JavaScript. If you're interested in taking front-end web technologies more seriously, then consider investing the time in this workshop.

This PreCompiler will be much more than a pedestrian review of information you could easily glean from a README or a written tutorial. Instead, attendees will be given opinionated, hands-on tour of how the presenters actually write code at their day jobs. That means we'll introduce the "vanilla" Jasmine API, but we'll quickly pivot to a workflow that we believe is even better; with tools like jasmine-fixture, jasmine-stealth, jasmine-given, and CoffeeScript. 

The workshop will be punctuated by a number of pair-programming labs: starting with a basic test-driven-development exercise, moving onto testing more complex object interactions, and graduating to AJAX and DOM manipulation situations that in a real web application.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Justin Searls</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Realworld-JavaScript-Testing-Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Andrew Vida</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Andy Vida is a developer at Test Double, a software studio in Columbus, OH. When he's not building stuff with things, he relishes in helping others learn and grow. He is an aspiring homebrewer, and guitarist, appreciates all things tech related, classic cars and spending time with his family.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>61d56f12-5879-42d7-850e-9f4bc553842c</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Justin-Searls</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Responsive JavaScript: Not Your Momma's JS</Title>
		<Abstract>Responsive Web Design (RWD) is all the rage. As the industry explores the patterns and design challenges of RWD, we need to examine the ways in which we write the JavaScript that powers the interactions. RWD has also presented some design challenges that CSS alone isn't ready for. We'll take a look at some of the leading JavaScript solutions to solve some of these problems as well as some of the problems that have still need solutions.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Rob Tarr</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Responsive-JavaScript-Not-Your-Mommas-JS</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>d4f96d04-6bf8-40ce-af58-1c0007d80fb8</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Rob-Tarr</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Rethinking Errors: Learning from Scala and Go</Title>
		<Abstract>C++ brought exceptions to mainstream programming, and Java goes further with checked exceptions. Both languages treat exceptions as the one way to report all kinds of errors. The Scala and Go languages introduce a new idea: There is more than one kind of error. Thus, there should be more than one kind of error reporting, and multiple different kinds of responses to errors. I&#x2019;ll show some of the history and past experiments in error handling, then look at how Scala and Go approach the error problem in a better way.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Bruce Eckel</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Rethinking-Errors-Learning-from-Scala-and-Go</URI>
		<Id>6aa91b39-bb3b-4e7e-8106-35d1a776d877</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Bruce-Eckel</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Riding the Metro: Real World Stories from the Trenches</Title>
		<Abstract>If you are planning a Windows 8 app, you might want to hear from the trenches. Bill has been working full time on Windows Store apps and writing a book on programming Windows 8 for over a year. Come hear what he has learned about using Windows 8 every day as a development environment, coding in JavaScript for the desktop, async programming in a single threaded language, interacting with Windows 8 programmatically, and more.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Aloeswood/Leopardswood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Bill Sempf</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Windows 8</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Riding-the-Metro-Real-World-Stories-from-the-Trenches</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>022957ca-a898-4c7c-bd37-5eeeaf155566</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Bill-Sempf</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Rounding out whole-team quality through exploration (Tuesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Do you ever get a creeping feeling there is more to software quality than test automation and clean code? Have you wondered about broader quality considerations beyond testing the specification? Have you tried to use smoke testing or ad-hoc testing to better inform quality issues, but don't get the results you're looking for? If so, this session can help by providing a refreshing aromatic blend of Exploratory Testing and visualization techniques your team can use instantly!
 
In this session you will learn a handful of light-weight practical approaches to round out your teams' quality wheelhouse. First, we will create a product quality strategy that will help guide your quality activities. Next, we will discuss Structured Exploratory Testing and practice creating charters to help inform on various aspects of quality. Finally, we will review some simple techniques for visualizing quality activities and enhance a team's workflow.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Matt Barcomb</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Rounding-out-wholeteam-quality-through-exploration-Tuesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Diane Zajac-Woodie</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Diane Zajac-Woodie (@agilesquirrel) is redefining the role of the Business Analyst as more than a requirements dictator. Through open and honest conversations coupled with problem-solving prowess, she guides the business toward creative solutions that actually solve problems and eliminate waste.  She shares this same approach with her technical teams, facilitating communication, cooperation and continuous learning to ensure success. Diane craves knowledge almost as much as chocolate and could make question-asking an Olympic sport. Her recent passion is to free those that are mired in the status quo even if she has to pull them out one at a time. Her alter ego makes her thoughts transparent on her blog, http://agilesquirrel.blogspot.com/.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>6797d50d-740f-44c3-9f7b-c79254756e1b</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Matt-Barcomb</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Ruby for (Possible) Converts (Wednesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>
Are you experienced in a language like C/C++/C# or Java? Are you a little Ruby-curious? This session is for you.

We'll start with a quick introduction to fundamental Ruby syntax and patterns, get you started on a project, then turn you loose to practice and discover.

Please note that this session is focusing on pure Ruby and will not dive into Rails.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Steve Klabnik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Ruby</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Ruby-for-Possible-Converts-Wednesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Franklin Webber</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Franklin Webber was once told that he is a great software developer and a terrible computer scientist. He writes software more for the user experience than the size of its Big O Notation. His professional experience comes from a testing background where he sought to automate himself out of a job. This brought him to software development where he became the resident generalist always willing to step up and learn technologies. He believes his empathy has helped him the most in being able to communicate and teach to peers and students. </SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>b6f91806-faac-4625-b134-2282d8640964</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Steve-Klabnik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Ruby Style and Object-Oriented Programming (Wednesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>Ruby has a cute syntax and a rich set of libraries -- but neither is useful in the long run without and understanding of how to design Ruby objects. What does a good method look like? When should you use codules instead of classes? How do you take advantage of blocks?
Optional parameters? Duck typing?

If you are familiar with the basis of Ruby syntax, this session can help take your design to the next level. We'll pursue a solution to a simple project while emphasizing the design of modules, classes, methods and lines of code. We'll look at a few methods for abstraction and refactoring, especially focusing on techniques that show off Ruby's more unusual capabilities and patterns.

Please note that this session is focusing on pure Ruby and will not dive into Rails.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Steve Klabnik</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Ruby</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Ruby-Style-and-ObjectOriented-Programming-Wednesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Franklin Webberl</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Franklin Webber was once told that he is a great software developer and a terrible computer scientist. He writes software more for the user experience than the size of its Big O Notation. His professional experience comes from a testing background where he sought to automate himself out of a job. This brought him to software development where he became the resident generalist always willing to step up and learn technologies. He believes his empathy has helped him the most in being able to communicate and teach to peers and students. </SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>c9529f36-d5fb-4907-b5a6-a7f10c6828d5</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Steve-Klabnik</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>RubyMotion for iOS</Title>
		<Abstract>RubyMotion is a brand new project built by the creator of MacRuby that finally brings the power of native Ruby application development to iOS. RubyMotion gives you a way to quickly bootstrap, compile, deploy code written in Ruby that accesses all the raw power of the Cocoa Touch and Core Foundation APIs.

Under the hood, Objective C shares a lot in common with RubyMotion. It's not a translated bridge. The Ruby object model is built right on top of the Objective C runtime. We'll explore how it works, get a taste of its flexibility, see some demos in action, and talk about the pitfalls that await the brave souls who live on the cutting edge.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jonathan Penn</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/RubyMotion-for-iOS</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>cc88431a-742d-4ac3-9523-e468ce17fbce</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jonathan-Penn</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Scala as a Better Java</Title>
		<Abstract>One of the major C++ design goals was to bring C programmers into a world of better programming by allowing them to primarily program in what they know (C), and add C++ features as they learn them. This way, C++ got &#x201C;the camel&#x2019;s nose inside the tent&#x201D; (and the rest of it eventually followed). This presentation will emphasize the advantages of &#x201C;Programming Java in Scala&#x201D; by translating selected examples from Thinking in Java 4th Edition. You&#x2019;ll learn how you can make your Java life much better by coding in Scala.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Bruce Eckel</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Scala</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Scala-as-a-Better-Java</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>603a3abe-acef-4bc2-90b4-8b42e3802f87</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Bruce-Eckel</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Secrets of Awesome JavaScript API Design</Title>
		<Abstract>It doesn't take long for most developers to sniff out a poorly-designed JavaScript API. Within minutes of reading about or coding against a new library, most developers can intuit whether their long-term relationship with that library will be a pleasant or unfortunate one. While documentation, buzz and other factors certainly play into that conclusion, the largest influencer of that snap conclusion is the "feel" of the API itself. APIs are developer UX: A good one raises a developers enjoyment; a bad one sends it plummeting. 

As developers, we know what good and bad JavaScript APIs "feel" like, and yet we struggle with designing the kind of APIs that we enjoy using. But principles of good JavaScript API design do exist, and it's possible to extract them from several key libraries in the the proliferating JavaScript landscape. In this session, Brandon Satrom will do exactly that, digging into the design aspects of popular libraries like jQuery, Backbone, Knockout, Modernizer, Kendo UI and others to enumerate the designed-in qualities of these libraries that make them not only popular, but a pleasure to use.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Nile</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Brandon Satrom</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Secrets-of-Awesome-JavaScript-API-Design</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>60421aa5-f1b7-4ae2-b432-d081dc2130a7</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Brandon-Satrom</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Simple and Beautiful Rails Code with Functional Style</Title>
		<Abstract>Do you have to look at Rails models with 1400 lines of code? Or 80 line method loaded with iterators, conditionals and instance variables? Not only you, even the code author does not understand what's going on in there.

I'll show you how you can craft simple and beautiful Rails application by adopting functional programming inspired ideas. Say goodbye to the mess you have by constructing tiny classes and functions that you can use to build up a complex system.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Attila Domokos</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Ruby</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Simple-and-Beautiful-Rails-Code-with-Functional-Style</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>8bfcb962-1831-49e3-9259-f23800e37934</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Attila-Domokos</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Speaker Workshop (Tuesday All Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>Interested in becoming a great speaker? Come learn or hone your skills with some of the nation's best speakers. You'll get the chance to learn tips and tricks, and you'll have the chance to get feedback on your own presentation methods.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Banyan</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Leon Gersing</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Public Speaking</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Speaker-Workshop-Tuesday-All-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>a09e645b-0867-4880-adb7-7f525763a95e</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Leon-Gersing</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Straight-Up Design: Simple Ways for Devs to Make Apps Look and Work Better</Title>
		<Abstract>It&#x2019;s a question that designers in the coding world hear all the time from developers: &#x201C;How do I make my stuff look better on my own?&#x201D; It&#x2019;s all very well and good to learn about design theory, but sometimes  - such as on side projects with no design support, or when you want to work more comfortably and fluidly with your company&#x2019;s internal designers - you just want to know exactly what to do to polish your applications. We&#x2019;ll discuss topics like finding good design inspiration, choosing fonts and colors, understanding visual hierarchy and messaging, improving overall user experience, and what frameworks and tools exist to help make your design work easier.

(This is more or less the &#x201C;sequel&#x201D; to the &#x201C;Developers Can&#x2019;t Design (And Other Completely Untrue Design Myths)&#x201D; presented last year at Codemash.)</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jen Myers</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Design/UX</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/StraightUp-Design-Simple-Ways-for-Devs-to-Make-Apps-Look-and-Work-Better</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>a1132d23-b4cd-4986-bab5-8f33aea68722</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jen-Myers</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Subcut: Simple Injection Dependency Framework in Scala</Title>
		<Abstract>About a year ago SubCut 1.0 was released and offered the simplest API for Scala dependency management that I could think of. It provides a DSL for easy configuration and binding of implementations to traits, a mixin trait for easy dependency lookup and injection, use of either mixins or implicit parameters to apply configuration to new instances, and an optional compiler plugin to remove the small amount of repeated boilerplate that showed up through the code when using implicit parameters.

To my surprise and great pleasure, people started to use SubCut - it scratched an itch with other people than just me. I also got committers on the project in github, and some fantastic improvements were submitted. During the same period, I and others continued to use SubCut and found some functional limitations in the current implementation. These things prompted work on a 2.0 release of subcut which has made a number of improvements to the API and functionality.

This session will cover what SubCut is and how it works, what is new in 2.0, and a more general look at working backwards from a desired API which emphasizes simplicity, an approach which is sometimes overlooked in the creation of Scala APIs.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Orange</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Dick Wall</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Scala</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Subcut-Simple-Injection-Dependency-Framework-in-Scala</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>7aae33ae-44ff-4647-99bb-5639f12dc048</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Dick-Wall</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Taking the Microcontrollers to the Next Level - Make Your Very Own PCB circuit board</Title>
		<Abstract>What do you think two geeks do when they have too much time on their hands? They have fun with microcontrollers. In this session, Min and Lwin will start off with basics on electronics, safety while playing with electricity to take your life style to the next level. They will actually show you step by steps on how to design and make your own printed circuit board from scratch. We will bring etching solution, we will etch out a board with you. Then we will use the popular arduino and netduino platform to control the board remotely from a mobile device.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon G</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Lwin Maung</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Hardware</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Taking-the-Microcontrollers-to-the-Next-Level--Make-Your-Very-Own-PCB-circuit-board</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Min Maung</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>In his &#x201C;spare&#x201D; time, Min Maung is a skilled, cross-platform mobile developer, aggressive hackathon competitor and a speaker. Enamored with the Window Phone UI, Min co-created the first Metro UI launcher for Android, featured technical sites such as Engadget, Gizmodo, and Pocket Now. He also wrote soon to publish &#x201C;Accolade Navigator,&#x201D; a turn-by-turn, visually compelling GPS navigation system for the Windows Phone. When he&#x2019;s not coding, he&#x2019;s building robots using Robotic Studio and powering them with microcontrollers attachements that he personally designed and created from scratch. Monday through Friday, you&#x2019;ll find him at a leading, privately-held payroll and HR sofware solutions company, cranking out .Net code and writing apps in ASP.Net, Silverlight, and other .Net solutions.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>8110070c-6e53-4de9-95a6-c736d3690b8f</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Lwin-Maung</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Taking your Android Apps to the Cloud with Windows Azure Mobile Services</Title>
		<Abstract>Android is fast becoming the number one mobile OS for development. If you want to build Android apps, you NEED to know about using the cloud. In this session, we&#x2019;ll talk about connecting Android apps to Windows Azure Mobile Services to take advantage of easy data storage, user auth with multiple providers, push notifications and more. You&#x2019;ll leave knowing how to get an easy to use backend up and running and focus on building a great app.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Chris Risner</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Taking-your-Android-Apps-to-the-Cloud-with-Windows-Azure-Mobile-Services</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>07acf95a-4f74-449d-9911-9dcc78f3a934</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Chris-Risner</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Test Driving User Interfaces</Title>
		<Abstract>Test Driving business and persistence logic has been proven to be an effective technique for incremental design, reduced complexity, and easy automated regression testing. Many teams struggle with how to achieve these same benefits for User Interfaces. The traditional notion is that a UI is too fragile and hard to test until it is already built.

This session will consist of a brief explanation of the Page Object pattern, followed by a live coding demo showing the integration of Cucumber-JVM with Selenium via Page Objects. Code will be available on GitHub after the session.

Attendees will come away with an understanding of:
 * the benefits of consolidating structural web page information in a single location
 * how the Page Object pattern can be applied to an existing project
 * the limitations of the Page Object pattern</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Nayan Hajratwala</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Test-Driving-User-Interfaces</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>5bb9761d-cebf-4d0b-941c-f0b70e5772fe</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Nayan-Hajratwala</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Testable JavaScript</Title>
		<Abstract>Your client-side JavaScript is code as worthy of testing as any server-side code that you might write, but often JavaScript testing is ignored. This session will introduce you to QUnit, Jasmine, and Mocha, three popular JavaScript testing frameworks. Come see how you can easily incorporate TDD/BDD techniques into your web development stack and increase your confidence that your JavaScript code is as robust as your server-side code.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>James Kovacs</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Testable-JavaScript</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>241ae148-99af-4e80-9f5d-0e9c536f49a1</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/James-Kovacs</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Testing Code From The Pit Of Despair</Title>
		<Abstract>Michael Feathers defines Legacy Code as any code that doesn&#x2019;t have automated tests, and you agree that automated tests are an important facet of successful software development. Then it happens &#x2013; you get your next assignment, and it&#x2019;s your worst nightmare! You have to maintain and enhance a large application that has no tests in place, and there are parts that are just plain scary. Where do you start? Traditional Test Driven Development techniques don&#x2019;t typically work, since they focus on an inside-out development paradigm.

I will show you the patterns and practices that will help you turn the scary big ball of mud into a tested code base.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Philip Japikse</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Testing-Code-From-The-Pit-Of-Despair</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>bfb02880-faef-41a9-9ef7-10adfaed19d2</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Philip-Japikse</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Testing Web Applications with Geb</Title>
		<Abstract>If you build web applications and cringe at the phrase "but how are we going to test it?" you're going to love Geb: the browser automation and testing tool. Geb is a Groovy framework for testing web applications: it builds on Selenium, but draws ideas from jQuery and elsewhere to make it productive and fun to test your applications in-browser.

Geb is rich with ideas to keep your tests clear, concise and maintainable. It is useful in all major testing frameworks: JUnit, TestNG, and Spock. We'll see how to navigate around the browser, clicking links, submitting forms, and verifying results. We'll also see Geb Pages and Modules, which allow you to define elements inside a page once, and reference them across many tests. Basically, Geb removes the excuses for not testing your web application, and that's a great thing!</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T16:00:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Howard Lewis Ship</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Java</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Testing-Web-Applications-with-Geb</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>5f5d957e-9945-48a5-b82d-c39e596aa31e</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Howard-Lewis-Ship</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Testing: It's Not Just for Your Code</Title>
		<Abstract>Nearly every conference we attend, we're bombarded with modern testing practices. Test Driven Development. Behavior Driven Development. Acceptance Tests. Unit Tests. Integration Tests. Factories. Cucumber. RSpec. Test Unit. On and on and on it goes. These are great tools for our tool belts, but they're all focused on a small portion of our software life cycles; mainly the developer portion.

There is a world outside of red green refactor. In this presentation, we'll take a look at where and how things go wrong. With all green tests and complete coverage, we can use different kinds of tests to reduce the pain, prevent regressions, and deliver strong deployments long after the features are completed.

We've tested our code. Now let's think about Testing Everything Else!

We'll focus on 3 main areas of issue:

- Environment: "It's works on my machine", "The Macbook Pro Bubble", "What Firewall?", "Connection String Blues" and other common issues.

- Data Issues: "Garbage In, Garbage Out", "Legacy Business Constraints vs New Technology",  "Real World Data vs Developer Data", "Index/Duplicate Record Madness".

- Deployments:  "All Test Pass Myth", "Customers vs. Steakholders", "Server Side Tests", and "We Don't Need QA".

Slide deck:  https://speakerdeck.com/u/claco/p/testing-its-not-just-for-your-code
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Portia/Wisteria</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Christopher H. Laco</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Testing-Its-Not-Just-for-Your-Code</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>cf708351-d24f-4b04-bb2d-b4191a373a17</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Christopher-H-Laco</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>The Class that Knew too Much: Refactoring Spaghetti Code</Title>
		<Abstract>The Single Responsibility Principle states that a class should have one (and only one) reason to change. Classes that don't adhere to this principle can result in tightly coupled spaghetti code that leads to more bugs and higher maintenance. We'll look at how to identify these classes by using some heuristics and looking for "code smells", and we'll clean them up using refactoring tools, design patterns, dependency injection and even aspect-oriented programming. Examples will be in C#, but the concepts can be applied to a variety of languages.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Indigo Bay</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Matthew D. Groves</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/The-Class-that-Knew-too-Much-Refactoring-Spaghetti-Code</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>f35688cf-f4ae-45fe-af08-618539e10abd</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Matthew-D-Groves</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>The Evolution of Asynchronous Programming on .NET </Title>
		<Abstract>Everything you wanted the know about asynchronous programming in .NET, but were afraid to ask. 

Multithreaded programming is hard.  the latest version of Visual Studio includes language additions to C# and VB to make it much easier to write asynchronous code (the async and await keywords).

.NET has had numerous ways to implement asynchonous and lenghty operations over the years.  This session details some of these techniques, their benefits and their drawbacks.  This session also details the progression of these techniques leading up to async/await in an effort to better understand the new syntax as well as better understand how to migrate existing asynchronous code to the new syntax.  As well, this session allows you to increase your expertise with several advanced language features that the new syntax and existing patterns build on, like lamdas, anonymous methods, closures, etc.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Guava/Tamarind</Room>
		<Difficulty>Advanced</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Peter Ritchie</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>.NET</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/The-Evolution-of-Asynchronous-Programming-on-NET-</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>d670b7f8-ccd9-493b-a98e-78653268a5dd</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Peter-Ritchie</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>The Holy Grail: Getting Your Customer to Write Acceptance Tests</Title>
		<Abstract>For as long as I've been testing code, we've talked about getting the customer to write the tests. Cucumber is the latest contender vying for this lofty goal. I largely passed on Cucumber as an additional step adding a needless layer of complexity between the tests and code. That's true as long as the customers aren't reading or writing the tests. By writing the specs at the appropriate level of detail, customers can actually engage in the process. The result is profound conversations with your customer about how the system actually works and how it should work. In this session, we'll walk through the feature development process and show how we get our customers involved.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Doug Alcorn</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/The-Holy-Grail-Getting-Your-Customer-to-Write-Acceptance-Tests</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>70edd817-e0d9-4b6f-83cc-19a726267005</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Doug-Alcorn</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>The Native/Mobile Web: Beyond the Basics with PhoneGap</Title>
		<Abstract>Phonegap (also known as Cordova) is a powerful cross-platform tool for building mobile applications with standard web technologies such as HTML5, JavaScript, and CSS.  While the framework is extremely simple, it can be difficult to make the switch from thinking about web applications to thinking about mobile applications.  There are performance pitfalls, and code-organization concerns, and tricky development environments.

In this talk, JC will walk us through a real working Phonegap application built using Backbone.js, Require.js, and a smattering of other open source tools and all covered by an automated test suite.  The presentation will cover the following:

- How to organize our application and its dependencies
- Dealing with local vs. remote data
- Creating a simple build process for packaging your app for deployment to multiple targets (iOS and Android)
- Dealing with the performance gotchas when working with web technologies on mobile devices
- Debugging a remote mobile web application</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Indigo Bay</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>JC Grubbs</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/The-NativeMobile-Web-Beyond-the-Basics-with-PhoneGap</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>c58bcf0c-a277-48e1-9a51-d53f14edb37c</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/JC-Grubbs</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Touring the Universe with Scientific Python</Title>
		<Abstract>Python is big in the world of science, bringing the power of a general-purpose language to domains traditionally dominated by languages like FORTRAN and Matlab. But the statistics and visualization power-tools that draw scientists to Python can be daunting at first for people in other fields. This talk will use a common human birthright, the sky full of stars and planets and galaxies, to take an illustrated whirlwind tour of the ways that Python can be used to analyze, process, and visualize complex science-grade data, and will then bring the lessons back home by showing how the same tools can be used on data like your Apache logs, user demographics, and application performance. And you might even learn a bit of astronomy in the process!</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon E</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Brandon Rhodes</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Python</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Touring-the-Universe-with-Scientific-Python</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>1f57462a-d579-4b8e-8122-8c3ca6326842</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Brandon-Rhodes</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Understanding Prototypal Inheritance</Title>
		<Abstract>One the most misunderstood concepts in JavaScript is prototypal inheritance.  Prototypal inheritance is nothing like classical inheritance but is actually quiet easy to grasp once you let go of the bounds of classes and instances.  In this session we will explore the nature of JavaScript objects, how they inherit from one another, and why everyone thought this prototype stuff was so hard in the first place.  If you want to up your game and really understand how JavaScript inheritance works, come check out this session.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Guy Royse</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>JavaScript</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Understanding-Prototypal-Inheritance</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>88f60228-ca35-4213-8bdd-c9bb830f8668</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Guy-Royse</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Using Capistrano For Deploying Everything</Title>
		<Abstract>Teams are too afraid of deploying code. Since shipping code is painful, they put it off and do less of it. No good. We need to make deployment easy and enjoyable. Capistrano is a fantastic remote server automation tool which works wonderfully for automating deployments and other server tasks. Written in Ruby, it has seen a lot of adoption for deploying rails applications. Since falling in love with this library, our office decided to apply it to every project we're involved with &#x2014; including PHP content management systems. We will cover a brief introduction to Capistrano and discuss real world examples of how we've used it to make our team more productive. Automating deployment has changed the way we work in a great way. </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Cypress</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Rob Harr</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Continuous Deployment</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Using-Capistrano-For-Deploying-Everything</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>d7b1d987-49bb-47e5-bf4d-9844a9486061</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Rob-Harr</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Using Images in iOS</Title>
		<Abstract>This talk will cover using images in iOS, from loading from the disk and network efficiently to creating images from scratch in your iOS app. WIth five separate screen resolutions to account for, images can quickly get out of hand, increasing the size of your binary and making it a nightmare to support. We'll look at making stretchable images that can support any resolution, creating thumbnails of large images, and even look at a new library I've created for rendering images on the fly. </Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T21:50:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jeff Kelley</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Using-Images-in-iOS</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>41e592e8-a14b-49a3-aa34-4ed88b2f20c7</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jeff-Kelley</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Vendor Sessions - Friday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T20:20:00Z</End>
		<Room>TBD</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Vendor-Sessions--Friday</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>43720cb8-d8ca-4694-8806-debcbdefa239</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Vendor Sessions - Thursday</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-10T20:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-10T20:20:00Z</End>
		<Room>TBD</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Vendor-Sessions--Thursday</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>2df202e4-219c-4efb-a838-3898d183dd19</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Version your database on nearly any platform with Liquibase</Title>
		<Abstract>If you are still writing one-off scripts to manage your database, then it is time to make your life much simpler and less error-prone.  
We'll spend the time discussing Liquibase, a tool that will help you to manage that process.  It will even allow you to check your schema and seed data into source-control, and get new environments up and running quickly.  This session will focus not on the merits of using such a tool, but on its workflow and implementation in a project.  We'll run through the majority of features from the command-line, demonstrating that as long as a Java Runtime Environment (jre) is available, Liquibase can be used during deployments on any platform.  We'll also touch on usage with maven and quirks of Liquibase that are good to know ahead of time.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Daniel Bower</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Continuous Deployment</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Version-your-database-on-nearly-any-platform-with-Liquibase</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>4abb3869-bacd-42e1-93dc-14e712090b65</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Daniel-Bower</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Vital Testing (Tuesday Half Day PM)</Title>
		<Abstract>This workshop is for the testing-minded developer who would like to sharpen their testing skills. Are you unsatisfied with the your test coverage? Or maybe you find that your unit tests tend to break when you refactor. Or maybe you just can't seem to get your tests to help drive your design direction.

Whatever your testing shortcomings, this workshop will allow you to practice your testing skills is a series of short, focused coding exercises. The workshop will begin with a talk on testing strategies and skills covering things like: starting with failing test; selecting what to test next; making sure the test fails; focusing on behavior, not implementation; and writing readable, non-brittle tests.

After the talk you will participate in a testing self assessment to see where you need to improve. The rest of the workshop will be an opportunity to pair with like-minded individuals and practice those skills that need improvement.

Testing is no longer an optional part of software development, it is an integral part of writing solid code. Come join us as we improve this vital skill.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-08T18:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-08T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>D</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jim Weirich</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Vital-Testing-Tuesday-Half-Day-PM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Matt Darby</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Matt Darby is a Senior Developer at NewContext, holds a MSCS, can brew beer, and takes obscure music trivia way too seriously. Husband, Dad, Rubyist, storyteller and a swell fella. He also leads the Columbus Ruby Brigade and sports a fine goatee.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>3738d0a0-0aa9-4afe-9eb5-82b315f4616c</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jim-Weirich</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Waterpark Party</Title>
		<Start>2013-01-11T03:00:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-11T06:00:00Z</End>
		<Room>Waterpark</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>All Attendees</SpeakerName>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Waterpark-Party</URI>
		<EventType>Fun</EventType>
		<Id>4db66333-cc1e-4718-8e52-6634c1fd6869</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/All-Attendees</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Web Design Process in a Responsive World</Title>
		<Abstract>Front-end developers have had their day playing with fluid grids, flexible content, and media queries. Now it's time to let the rest of the team in on the process. We'll discuss:

&#x2022; why responsive web design cannot be a front-end-only job
&#x2022; getting into the browser as soon as possible
&#x2022; new client deliverables
&#x2022; setting client expectations
&#x2022; some ideas on how to price RWD
&#x2022; a new process for a new web

This will be a session for anyone who works on the web. We are not writing code, we're discussing how to embrace the fluidity of the web throughout your entire process. Bring your opinions.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T14:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon H</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Ben Callahan</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Design/UX</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Web-Design-Process-in-a-Responsive-World</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Drew Clemens</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>Drew Clemens is the Director of Content Strategy for Sparkbox, a design and development shop leading the charge for a more fluid web. With experience in retail design, product development, and a keen eye for creative communications, Drew approaches the web with a wholistic and pragmatic approach. He works with a passion for the effective combination of strategic planning, fresh design, clear content, and cutting-edge technology.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>382647a3-d874-47b2-854c-89a9edb1341a</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Ben-Callahan</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Web Development with Python and Django (Wednesday Full Day)</Title>
		<Abstract>New to web development? Want to check out a new language? Join us in an exploration of Python by way of the Django web framework. Python has been around for over 20 years and has a well-deserved reputation of being easy to learn and very useful for quick prototyping. Django is a web framework written in Python "for perfectionists with deadlines." We'll introduce the Python language and the Django framework through a project that will result in a fully functional, tested site where users can submit proposals and receive feedback. We'll cover some of the neat time-saving applications that ship with Django and finish with a simple read-only JSON/REST API that could be used to power mobile applications. No Python or web development experience is required; we'll provide the HTML, CSS and Javascript so you can focus on server-side development. Bring your laptop and join us for a tour of Python and Django!</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T22:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Indigo</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Michael Crute</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Python</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Web-Development-with-Python-and-Django-Wednesday-Full-Day</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<SecondarySpeakerName>Mike Pirnat</SecondarySpeakerName>
		<SecondarySpeakerBio>A Python nerd of 12 years and active in web development for over 15, Mike works at online greeting leader AG Interactive, where he serves as a wandering samurai, doer of deeds, righter of wrongs, integrator of systems, wrangler of code, bearer of standards, seeker of truth, advocate of excellence, educator, mentor, craftsman, and catalyst.  He is also a co-host and producer of From Python Import Podcast.</SecondarySpeakerBio>
		<Id>470b3e95-b679-4b9b-aa0f-d2a2e1794a35</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Michael-Crute</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Web Testing with Ruby and Cucumber (Wednesday Half Day AM)</Title>
		<Abstract>
This workshop introduces the practice of using Ruby and Cucumber for testing web applications.  Through a series of targeted hands on exercises, this workshop introduces Cucumber and Ruby scripting, using page objects to make your tests more maintainable, different strategies for maintaining your test data in order to make your tests more effective and simple, simple navigation through the pages of the application, extending Cucumber using World, Transformations, and writing our own RSpec matchers. Cheezy will also walk you through how to use a few of his Ruby gems to structure your test suite to minimize maintenance over the lifecycle of your tests. Make no mistake, this is a hands on workshop and you will be writing a lot of code.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-09T13:30:00Z</Start>
		<End>2013-01-09T17:30:00Z</End>
		<Room>Sagewood/Zebrawood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Jeff Morgan</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Testing</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Web-Testing-with-Ruby-and-Cucumber-Wednesday-Half-Day-AM</URI>
		<EventType>PreCompiler</EventType>
		<Id>dfdf4be7-0807-4f6a-b89b-11da161f2dfd</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Jeff-Morgan</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Windows 8 and Windows Phone with Azure</Title>
		<Abstract>With phones, slates, tablets and other devices exploding in market share, it&#x2019;s important to know what technologies and tools will help you develop better applications. These devices are often short on processing power and storage, which is where Azure can really help out. Come see what it&#x2019;s like to use Azure with Windows 8 Store Apps and Windows Phone, including several examples with push notifications, storage and authentication.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T14:30:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Beginner</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Greg Levenhagen</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Windows 8</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Windows-8-and-Windows-Phone-with-Azure</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>d14694dc-d829-4f0c-9aa2-96d356abfd23</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Greg-Levenhagen</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Windows Azure: Lessons from the Field</Title>
		<Abstract>The demos and presentations that show you how awesome a certain technology is are certainly exciting. But, let&#x2019;s be real &#x2013; there are often times when the demo &#x201C;happy path&#x201D; doesn&#x2019;t work for real-world projects. Creating production ready Windows Azure applications often requires deviating from the &#x201C;next, next, publish, magic, let&#x2019;s party&#x201D; path often seen. In this session we will pull back the curtain on common Windows Azure scenarios such as debugging and diagnostics, environment setup, build and deployment process, Access Control Service (ACS), and role upgrades &#x2013; just to name a few. Coming away from this session you&#x2019;ll have gained valuable, real-world inspired knowledge you can apply to your Windows Azure applications right now!</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-10T18:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Rosewood</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Michael S. Collier</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Other</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Windows-Azure-Lessons-from-the-Field</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>11da1b64-ea5d-4449-83ce-df0df70a390e</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Michael-S-Collier</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Windows Phone + SignalR = Awesome Possibilities!</Title>
		<Abstract>Built from the ground-up, Windows Phone brings together what you care about most, and brings it to you in an innovative and simple Modern UI interface. You and your content are at the center of it all through the Start screen experience with Live Tiles and integrated Hubs which provide rich &amp; continuous user experience. SignalR, on the other hand, is a very cool piece of technology that provides async signaling library to build real-time, multi-user interactive applications connecting disparate systems.

We start by introducing &amp; using SignalR, before taking its applications to mobile frameworks. What do you get when we combine personalization of Windows Phone &amp; the adaptability of SignalR? We get instant real-time communication between phone &amp; backend server. We get location service applications. Chat. Stocks. Alerts. Endless possibilities! Come join us as we explore some of these new opportunities through demos &amp; code samples.
</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T15:45:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Zambezi</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Samidip Basu</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mobile</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Windows-Phone--SignalR--Awesome-Possibilities</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>58ee003e-aac1-4698-b5a7-84898db5a497</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Samidip-Basu</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
	<Session>
		<Title>Working with Maps in iOS 6: MapKit and CoreLocation in Depth</Title>
		<Abstract>Adding a Map to an App and recording a User&#x2019;s location as they use the App has become a common must have feature in may of todays popular applications. This presentation will go over the updated iOS 6 APIs for accomplishing such tasks including map annotations, dragging and dropping custom pins as well as delve into some of the finer aspects of the required location based calculations one needs to consider to find the center of the map or the distance between two points. Additionally the presentation will go over techniques to update a MapView with a moving object as well as positioning the image for the object properly along its heading. This will be a straight forward hands on development presentation with plenty of code examples.</Abstract>
		<Start>2013-01-11T20:35:00Z</Start>
		<End xsi:nil="true"/>
		<Room>Salon A</Room>
		<Difficulty>Intermediate</Difficulty>
		<SpeakerName>Geoffrey Goetz</SpeakerName>
		<Technology>Mac/iPhone</Technology>
		<URI>/api/sessions.xml/Working-with-Maps-in-iOS-6-MapKit-and-CoreLocation-in-Depth</URI>
		<EventType>Session</EventType>
		<Id>4f248d87-0e18-488d-8cef-5e4130b8bb20</Id>
		<SpeakerURI>/api/speakers.xml/Geoffrey-Goetz</SpeakerURI>
	</Session>
</Sessions>
